<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Chinese Zodiac</title>
	<atom:link href="https://chinesezodiac.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/</link>
	<description>Explore Chinese Zodiac Signs and Traditional Wisdom</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 08:58:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2025 Rat Love Horoscope: Navigating the Highs and Lows of Romance</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-rat-love-horoscope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 08:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Love Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2025, the Year of the Snake (乙巳), people born in the Year of the Rat will experience a mix of both good and bad fortune in their love lives.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 2025, the Year of the Snake (乙巳), people born in the Year of the Rat will experience a mix of both good and bad fortune in their love lives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Potential Opportunities</strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Relationship Growth</strong>: Singles may have the chance to meet someone special, while married individuals will enjoy a warm and harmonious family atmosphere.</li>



<li><strong>Flourishing Romantic Luck</strong>: The Snake Year brings strong romantic energy, greatly enhancing your appeal to the opposite sex. Singles are likely to encounter someone they are drawn to, while married Rats should be cautious and avoid unnecessary romantic distractions.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Potential Challenges</strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Relationship Crisis</strong>: Emotional turbulence and relationship crises may arise. Married individuals should be cautious of infidelity, while singles could find themselves tangled in complicated love triangles.</li>



<li><strong>Frequent Arguments</strong>: Couples may experience ongoing conflicts and disagreements. Poor communication and differing opinions could challenge your relationship.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Key Points to Watch Out</strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Control Your Emotions, Avoid Impulsiveness</strong>: Emotions may fluctuate, so it&#8217;s important to control your temper and avoid impulsive actions that could harm your relationship.</li>



<li><strong>Enhance Communication, Resolve Misunderstandings</strong>: Communication is the bridge in relationships. Be sure to talk openly with your partner and clear up any misunderstandings promptly to prevent small issues from escalating.</li>



<li><strong>Stick to Your Principles, Resist Temptations</strong>: With strong romantic luck, it’s crucial to maintain your values and resist unnecessary temptations to avoid entanglements.</li>



<li><strong>Value Family, Cherish Your Relationship</strong>: For married individuals, family should be the top priority. Appreciate your bond with your partner and spend quality time with family to create a warm and harmonious home environment.</li>
</ul>



<p>In 2025, your love fortune will have its highs and lows. Seize the good opportunities and manage the challenges to enjoy a fulfilling and happy relationship. Wishing you smooth and joyful love life!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Monthly Horoscope for Rat (Year of the Wood Snake)</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-monthly-horoscope-for-rat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 08:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Monthly Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Year of the Snake (2025) offers growth and challenges. Career prospects are strong in January, with unexpected financial gains in June and December. However, critical months like May, September, and November may bring stress, financial struggles, or emotional swings. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Year of the Snake (2025) offers growth and challenges. Career prospects are strong in January, with unexpected financial gains in June and December. However, critical months like May, September, and November may bring stress, financial struggles, or emotional swings. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">January</h2>



<p>Career prospects are strong, with support from benefactors. Seize opportunities wisely.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">February</h2>



<p>Financial luck is favorable, but exercise caution in investments and avoid impulsive spending.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">March</h2>



<p>Romantic luck is smooth; singles may find opportunities to start a relationship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">April</h2>



<p>Pay attention to your health, particularly digestive issues. A light diet is recommended.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">May</h2>



<p>Career stress may peak; adjust your mindset and avoid emotional outbursts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">June</h2>



<p>Financial luck rebounds, with chances for unexpected gains. Plan your finances carefully.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">July</h2>



<p>Stable love luck ensures harmonious interactions with your partner.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">August</h2>



<p>Steady progress in your career; focus on diligence and avoid rushing for results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">September</h2>



<p>Financial struggles may arise. Practice frugality and avoid unnecessary expenses.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">October</h2>



<p>Romantic fluctuations could occur. Prioritize communication to prevent misunderstandings.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">November</h2>



<p>Career challenges may persist. Stay patient and avoid rash decisions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">December</h2>



<p>Financial luck improves, with potential investment returns. However, remain prudent in financial planning.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crisis Months</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>May: High career pressure and emotional swings. Take care of your mental health.</li>



<li>September: Financial downturns require cautious investment strategies to avoid losses.</li>



<li>November: Career stagnation calls for patience and careful decision-making.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key Advice</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Health: Prioritize digestive health and maintain a light, balanced diet.</li>



<li>Career: Stay grounded, seize opportunities, and avoid impulsive actions.</li>



<li>Finances: Plan carefully, invest cautiously, and minimize unnecessary expenditures.</li>



<li>Relationships: Foster open communication to avoid misunderstandings and cherish your relationships.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Horoscope for People Born in the Year of the Rat</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-horoscope-for-rat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 07:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Year of the Snake (乙巳) in 2025 will be a lucky year for you. Your overall fortune will see a noticeable improvement with the support of auspicious stars. Various aspects of your life will remain stable, and if you pursue further studies in a particular field, you could achieve significant new milestones.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Year of the Snake (乙巳) in 2025 will be a lucky year for you. Your overall fortune will see a noticeable improvement with the support of auspicious stars. Various aspects of your life will remain stable, and if you pursue further studies in a particular field, you could achieve significant new milestones.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Career</h2>



<p>You will receive help from benefactors at work and are likely to gain recognition and promotion from your superiors. However, pay attention to interpersonal relationships and avoid conflicts with colleagues.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Wealth</h2>



<p>Steady income from your main job will be complemented by good opportunities for additional earnings. There will be chances for investment and financial management, but proceed with caution to avoid blindly following trends.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Love</h2>



<p>Singles will experience strong romantic luck and are likely to meet someone they admire. For those who are married, relationships will remain stable, but communication is key to preventing misunderstandings.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Health</h2>



<p>Your physical health will be in good condition. However, maintain a regular diet and avoid overeating or indulging excessively.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Potential Risks</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Jealous Individuals</strong>: Be cautious of envious individuals who may try to sabotage your good fortune.</li>



<li><strong>Emotional Swings</strong>: The harmony of the year might lead to greater emotional volatility; manage your emotions carefully to avoid impulsive actions.</li>



<li><strong>Accidents and Hazards</strong>: The fiery energy of the Snake Year calls for vigilance against fire-related accidents and burns.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Suggestions</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Leverage your connections with benefactors by actively seeking opportunities.</li>



<li>Manage your finances wisely and avoid reckless investments.</li>



<li>Foster harmonious relationships with colleagues.</li>



<li>Maintain a positive mindset and avoid emotional reactions.</li>



<li>Prioritize safety by staying away from fire hazards and preventing accidents.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Monthly Horoscope for Ox (Year of the Wood Snake)</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-monthly-horoscope-for-ox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 08:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Monthly Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Steady progress with occasional challenges defines 2025 for Ox natives. Career growth appears in February and June, while May and October bring obstacles. Financial luck peaks in March but requires caution in July and December. Emotional ups and downs are frequent—communication is key. Protect your interests from gossipers and prioritize health with a balanced lifestyle.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Steady progress with occasional challenges defines 2025 for Ox natives. Career growth appears in February and June, while May and October bring obstacles. Financial luck peaks in March but requires caution in July and December. Emotional ups and downs are frequent—communication is key. Protect your interests from gossipers and prioritize health with a balanced lifestyle.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">January</h2>



<p>A steady month where caution is key. Focus on maintaining good interpersonal relationships and avoid gossip or disputes.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">February</h2>



<p>Career prospects improve with support from benefactors. However, pay attention to your health and balance work with rest.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">March</h2>



<p>Excellent financial luck with chances for unexpected gains. Romantic relationships remain stable, making this a good time to deepen connections.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">April</h2>



<p>An unstable month with emotional fluctuations. Be wary of gossipers and protect your secrets.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">May</h2>



<p>Challenges in your career may arise. Stay calm and adjust your mindset. Romantic difficulties may occur; avoid impulsive actions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">June</h2>



<p>Improved fortunes with new opportunities. However, prioritize your health and avoid overworking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">July</h2>



<p>Financial struggles may surface; focus on saving and spending wisely. Relationships may feel stagnant—enhance communication.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">August</h2>



<p>Career remains stable; success comes through steady effort. Romantic luck improves—seize the moment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">September</h2>



<p>Another unpredictable month with emotional ups and downs. Protect your interests and stay alert to potential betrayals.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">October</h2>



<p>Obstacles in career resurface; maintain a positive attitude. Romantic challenges may persist—avoid impulsiveness.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">November</h2>



<p>Fortunes recover with new opportunities on the horizon. Continue to monitor your health and avoid exhaustion.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">December</h2>



<p>Financial caution is advised. Romantic relationships remain calm; focus on meaningful communication.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Crisis Months</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>May</strong>: Career setbacks and romantic challenges.</li>



<li><strong>October</strong>: Difficulties in both career and relationships.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key Advice</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Cultivate strong relationships and avoid gossip or conflicts.</li>



<li>Balance work with rest to maintain good health.</li>



<li>Stay vigilant against gossipers and protect your interests.</li>



<li>Adapt your mindset to challenges and seize opportunities as they arise.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Career Horoscope for Ox: Steady Progress with Opportunities and Challenges</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-career-horoscope-for-ox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 08:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Career Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2025, Ox natives can expect steady career progress with opportunities for advancement. Supportive colleagues and recognition from leaders boost development, but conflicts may arise due to the Snake-Ox clash. Maintaining good relationships, improving skills, and balancing health with work are crucial for success.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 2025, Ox natives can anticipate gradual career growth with both opportunities and obstacles along the way.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Opportunities and Challenges</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Opportunities</strong>: Strong support from benefactors and recognition from leaders and colleagues will contribute to career development.</li>



<li><strong>Challenges</strong>: The clash between Snake and Ox signs (巳丑相刑) may invite interference from gossipers. Stay vigilant and handle matters cautiously.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Career Development</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>First Half of the Year</strong>: A stable period with steady progress. Focus on maintaining good workplace relationships to avoid conflicts.</li>



<li><strong>Second Half of the Year</strong>: Career prospects rise, with potential for breakthroughs. However, balance work and rest to avoid burnout.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Risks and Solutions</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Risks</strong>: The Snake-Ox clash increases the likelihood of workplace obstacles caused by gossipers or misunderstandings.</li>



<li><strong>Solutions</strong>: Stay low-key and avoid standing out too much. Strengthen communication with colleagues to resolve conflicts.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key Reminders</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Avoid Impulsiveness</strong>: Think carefully before acting to prevent poor decisions.</li>



<li><strong>Enhance Communication</strong>: Maintain strong communication with colleagues and leaders to stay informed and avoid misunderstandings.</li>



<li><strong>Improve Skills</strong>: Continuously upgrade your professional abilities to stay competitive.</li>



<li><strong>Prioritize Health</strong>: Stay mindful of your physical well-being, balancing work and rest to prevent exhaustion.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Suggestions</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Seize Opportunities</strong>: Be proactive and ambitious, but remain grounded and avoid rushing progress.</li>



<li><strong>Build Relationships</strong>: Foster strong connections with colleagues and leaders to mitigate obstacles caused by gossipers.</li>



<li><strong>Develop Skills</strong>: Keep learning and improving to gain a competitive edge.</li>



<li><strong>Stay Healthy</strong>: A healthy body and mind are essential for tackling career challenges effectively.</li>
</ul>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Financial Horoscope for Ox: Promising Opportunities with Risks to Manage</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-financial-horoscope-for-ox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Financial Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the Year of the Wood Snake (2025), Ox natives can expect a promising financial outlook, but potential risks require careful management.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-background" style="background:linear-gradient(90deg,rgb(255,245,203) 0%,rgb(182,227,212) 50%,rgb(51,167,181) 100%)">In the Year of the Wood Snake (2025), Ox natives can expect a promising financial outlook, but potential risks require careful management.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Financial Opportunities</strong><strong></strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Stable Income:</strong> Thanks to the Snake-Ox harmony (巳丑相合), steady earnings are assured. Outstanding work performance may bring raises or bonuses.</li>



<li><strong>Additional Gains:</strong> The Snake&#8217;s Fire element enhances the Ox&#8217;s Earth, improving opportunities for extra income through investments or side ventures.</li>



<li><strong>Support from Benefactors:</strong> Snake is a benefactor for Ox, offering valuable financial advice and opportunities for profit.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Financial Risks</strong><strong></strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Risk of Loss:</strong> The suppressive effect of Fire on Earth increases the likelihood of financial setbacks. Avoid impulsive spending and unnecessary expenses.</li>



<li><strong>Cautious Investments:</strong> The year is unfavorable for high-risk investments; proceed carefully to prevent significant losses.</li>



<li><strong>Interference from Gossipers:</strong> Be wary of deceitful individuals who might lead to financial losses or entanglements.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Tips for Financial Success</strong><strong></strong></h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Control Spending:</strong> Develop good financial habits and save for future needs by avoiding unnecessary purchases.</li>



<li><strong>Cautious Investments:</strong> Research thoroughly before investing, focusing on stable opportunities and avoiding trends or risky ventures.</li>



<li><strong>Stay Alert:</strong> Be mindful of dishonest individuals and protect yourself from scams or betrayals.</li>



<li><strong>Enhance Skills:</strong> Continuously improve your professional abilities to increase income potential through added value at work.</li>



<li><strong>Stay Positive:</strong> Even when facing financial challenges, maintain an optimistic outlook and actively seek solutions, trusting that difficulties will pass.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Summary</strong><strong></strong></h2>



<p>In 2025, Ox natives enjoy favorable financial prospects with stable earnings and opportunities for growth. By managing risks, controlling expenses, avoiding toxic influences, and focusing on personal development, they can achieve financial stability and prosperity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Ox Love Horoscope: Balance and Challenges in Relationships</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-ox-love-horoscope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2025 Love Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ox natives face a steady yet delicate love outlook in 2025, marked by potential conflicts and emotional swings. Strengthening communication, avoiding toxic relationships, and maintaining emotional stability are key to navigating challenges and fostering harmony in romantic connections.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-background" style="background-color:#f9f7f7">In 2025, the Year of the Wood Snake, love prospects for Ox natives are generally stable but carry hidden risks that require careful handling.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Potential Challenges</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Conflict (巳丑相刑): Tensions between Snake and Ox signs may lead to disputes, affecting relationship harmony.</li>



<li>Problematic Romance: While this year boosts romantic energy, Ox natives should beware of unhealthy relationships or emotional entanglements.</li>



<li>Emotional Swings: The Snake’s Fire element impacts the Ox’s Earth, leading to mood fluctuations that hinder communication.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tips for Success</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Control Emotions: Stay calm and avoid impulsive decisions that could harm your relationships.</li>



<li>Improve Communication: Maintain open dialogue with your partner to resolve misunderstandings early.</li>



<li>Avoid Toxic Relationships: Stay rational and cautious when evaluating romantic prospects.</li>



<li>Seek Support: If challenges arise, don’t hesitate to consult friends, family, or professionals for guidance.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Remedies</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Lucky Accessories: Wear charms featuring Rat or Rooster symbols to neutralize the conflict.</li>



<li>Feng Shui Enhancements: Place Snake-compatible items like red decorations or plants in your home to boost harmony.</li>



<li>Self-Care Practices: Engage in activities like reading or meditation to stabilize emotions and nurture relationships.</li>
</ul>



<p>Summary:</p>



<p>Ox natives face a balanced yet delicate love life in 2025. By addressing conflicts, avoiding toxic entanglements, and fostering emotional stability, they can overcome challenges and build stronger connections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2025 Horoscope for People Born in the Year of the Ox</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/2025-horoscope-for-ox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 07:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2025 Horoscope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=174</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year 2025, under the sign of the Wood Snake (乙巳), brings "刑" (conflict) between Snake (巳) and Ox (丑). This indicates a year of fluctuating fortunes, requiring caution and adaptability.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-ast-global-color-4-background-color has-background">The year 2025, under the sign of the Wood Snake (乙巳), brings &#8220;刑&#8221; (conflict) between Snake (巳) and Ox (丑). This indicates a year of fluctuating fortunes, requiring caution and adaptability.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Career</h2>



<p>The Fire element of Snake supports the Earth element of Ox, bringing potential career growth. However, due to the conflict between the signs, obstacles and competition may arise in the workplace. Stay patient and resilient; avoid impulsive decisions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Wealth</h2>



<p>The Fire of Snake exerts pressure on the Earth of Ox, leading to financial challenges. Be cautious with investments and avoid following trends blindly. Stable income from your main job is expected, but speculative ventures may not yield favorable results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Relationships</h2>



<p>The conflict between Snake and Ox signals difficulties in relationships. Singles may find it hard to form new connections, while married individuals might experience disagreements or conflicts. Open communication and mutual understanding are essential to navigate these challenges.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Health</h2>



<p>With the strong Fire influence, health issues may emerge. Pay attention to problems related to the digestive system or skin allergies. Maintain good dietary habits and ensure a regular sleep schedule to stay healthy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Warnings</h2>



<p>Trouble from Others: The Fire element of Snake (巳) supports the Earth element of Ox (丑), which can amplify the influence of ill-willed individuals. Be cautious of gossip and avoid unnecessary conflicts.</p>



<p>Emotional Instability: The conflict between Snake and Ox may lead to emotional fluctuations. Stay calm and avoid impulsive behavior.<br>Accidents and Mishaps: The restraining effect of Fire on Earth increases the risk of accidents. Prioritize safety, especially while traveling, and follow traffic rules diligently.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Suggestions</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Face challenges proactively and turn obstacles into opportunities for growth.</li>



<li>Handle finances carefully to avoid unnecessary losses.</li>



<li>Resolve conflicts through effective communication to strengthen relationships.</li>



<li>Pay attention to physical and mental health; maintain a positive and joyful attitude.</li>



<li>Wear zodiac-related lucky charms or place Feng Shui items to mitigate the negative effects of the sign conflict.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emotion-suppression Therapy</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/emotion-suppression-therapy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emotion-suppression therapy, a kind of psychological therapeutic method, is established under the guidance of theory of the five phases and restricting emotions. The therapy treats certain physical and mental ailments triggered by extreme emotions through restraining to remove the abnormal emotions. The theory and therapy concerning emotion-suppression first appear in Internal Classic. Being elaborated in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emotion-suppression therapy, a kind of psychological therapeutic method, is established under the guidance of theory of the five phases and restricting emotions. The therapy treats certain physical and mental ailments triggered by extreme emotions through restraining to remove the abnormal emotions.</p>



<p>The theory and therapy concerning emotion-suppression first appear in Internal Classic. Being elaborated in Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on Phenomena Corresponding to Yin and Yang, the emotions belong to five viscera and suppressing emotions (including &#8220;anger prevailing over thought&#8221; &#8220;thought prevailing over fear&#8221; &#8220;fear prevailing over joy&#8221; “joy prevailing over anxiety&#8221; &#8220;sorrow prevailing anger&#8221;), which are the rule of the five emotions that first appear in medical literature. Hereafter, being constantly supplemented and improved in terms of theory and clinical treatment, especially by Zhang Zihe, Zhu Danxi and other famous doctors in the Jin and Yuan dynasties, the therapy has become one of the main psychotherapies in TCM.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Contents</h2>



<p>Joy, anger, anxiety, thought, sorrow, fear and fright are called seven emotions in TCM. They&#8217;re the modal responses of people&#8217;s subjective feelings to external things. Ancient physicians attach great importance to the influence of emotional activities on the human body. In the course of long-term clinical observation, physicians realize that these modality reactions are intrinsically related to the visceral functions, and classify them with five viscera. In Internal Classic, joy is related to heart and belongs to fire; anger is related to liver and belongs to wood; anxiety (sorrow) is related to lung and belongs to metal; thought is related to spleen and belongs to the earth; fear is related to kidney and belongs to water. It is considered that human emotional activity is based on the essence of five viscera and is also one of the external manifestations of viscera. That is the connotation that&#8221; if five viscera are stable, blood vessel will run smoothly and the spirit will be eternal&#8221; in Spiritual Pivot: Fasting for Healthy People. If someone is suddenly subjected to intense mental stimulation or persistent mental trauma, his emotional activities will go beyond the scope of the body&#8217;s endurance and self-regulation, which will lead to the imbalance of Yin and Yang of the body, the inverse disorder of Qi and blood, and thereby impair the normal physiological functions of the viscera. The intense extreme emotion has its correlation and specificity on the impact of human visceral functions. Based on the damage of extreme emotion to human visceral activities, theories like &#8220;anger damaging liver&#8221; &#8220;joy damaging heart&#8221; &#8220;anxiety damaging spleen&#8221; &#8220;fear damaging kidney&#8221; &#8220;thought damaging spleen&#8221;, etc., are summarized by long-term clinical observation. At the same time, viscera give rise to pathological changes of deficiency and repletion which will generate abnormal emotional reactions of patients, such as &#8220;deficiency of heart Qi causing sorrow, while repletion causing consistent laughing&#8221;, &#8220;deficiency of liver Qi causing fear, while repletion causing anger&#8221;(Spiritual Pivot: Spirit-based Acupuncture), which is the sign of abnormal emotional changes of all viscera diseases.</p>



<p>The functions and activities of the viscera are closely related to each other. In order to maintain the physiological and psychological coordination and stability of the human body, the viscera are mutually generative and mutually restricting. This relationship is explained and reasoned by mutual generating and restraining among the five phases. In the theory of the five phases, the order of wood, fire, earth, metal and water are born one after another, which constitutes the promotion and generative relationship, and the lines of metal, wood, earth, water and fire are mutual restraining, which in turn constitutes the relationship of restraint and restriction. With the mutual generating and restraining between one thing and another, nature can be stable and unified; With the internal mutual generating and restraining of things, they can maintain coordination and development of themselves. Under the circumstance that extreme emotion damages the mental and physical homeostasis, physicians stimulate the phase being restricted to control the excess according to the five elements of emotions and their rules, so as to restore or reconstruct patients’ psychosomatic harmony, and achieve the purpose of treating the mental and physical diseases. Zhang Jingyue, a doctor of the Ming dynasty, emphasizes in the elaboration of emotion-suppression rules in Internal Classic that &#8220;if one of the five emotions is excessive, use the other to restrict it&#8221;, and he reveals the application basis and purpose of the therapy.</p>



<p>There are two treatments, the five emotions restricting therapy and looping therapy, which are described below.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Five Emotions Restricting Therapy</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. Anger Prevailing over Thought</h3>



<p>Thought is controlled by spleen and belongs to the earth. Thinking is a reflection of the process and ability of human beings to perceive things, which is not emotional in itself. People may feel anxious in that they are unable to understand or predict the outcome of an event. Therefore, in Internal Classic, &#8220;palpitation, thought and fright&#8221; and &#8220;anxiety and though&#8221; are described as one of the seven emotions. In daily life, excessive thinking caused by the things lingering in the heart or diligence often can cause symptoms of thought damaging spleen and dysfunction of spleen in transportation such as lack of appetite, abdominal fullness, and even anorexia, limb laziness. People who have been engaged in mental work for a long time suffer from insomnia, forgetfulness, palpitation and other signs</p>



<p>of mental nourishment failure due to excessive stress, which is believed in A-B Classic of Acupuncture and Moxibustion to be the cause of &#8220;thought comes from spleen and forms in heart&#8221;. Anger is liver&#8217;s emotion, and liver governs free coursing. Anger helps liver Qi rise, releasing bad emotions and rebuilding psychological balance. &#8220;Anger prevailing over thought&#8221; is the relationship of wood restraining earth from the perspective of the five phases. In terms of the physiological functions of the viscera, free coursing of liver Qi helps to activate spleen and release Qi. Therefore, in the clinical practice, methods such as deliberately disobeying the patient&#8217;s mind or taking away the patient&#8217;s beloved objects, etc. are often adopted to trigger his anger, so that the Qi can be released to the fullest extent, which can correct the pathological changes of &#8220;thought causing Qi stagnation&#8221;.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Thought Prevailing over Fear</h3>



<p>Fear is controlled by kidney and belongs to the water. It is a psychological reaction of the body, often associated with sudden shock, insecurity or fear in the face of an emergency or abnormal situation. Most of this fear will pass with time, and people need not worry about it. If people are exposed to a tense and fearful atmosphere for a long time, the body will always be in a state of stress, resulting in impaired physiological function. In severe cases, patients in sudden and continuous shock may have symptoms of &#8220;fear causing Qi sinking&#8221; such as urinary and fecal incontinence, seminal emission, efflux, diarrhea and so on. Patients often or persistently in fear will have restlessness, anxiety accompanied by the clinical symptoms of kidney damage and loss of essence, including bones and limbs weakness, thin and weak, even infertility so on. Treatment is often difficult to achieve by relying solely on medication without trying to free the patient from fear. Therefore, clinical treatment needs to be combined with psychological therapy like &#8220;thought prevailing over fear&#8217;. If the doctor can induce the patient to think according to the cause of fear and timidity, combining with the method of broadening their knowledge, strengthening their determination, thereby they can help patients gradually get rid of panic and fear.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. Fear Prevailing over Joy</h3>



<p>Joy is controlled by heart and belongs to the fire. &#8220;Joy causing Qi to slacken&#8221; mainly refers to the excessive joy will make people appear distracted, out of mind and spirit failing to keep to its abode. It is often characterized by an inability to concentrate, a trance, or even laughter in a state of madness. This kind of disease belongs to repletion pattern in that the treatment in clinic is mainly to clear heart and reduce fire. Fear causes timidity of Qi. If a doctor suddenly uses things that patients are usually afraid of to treat just like putting out fire with water, that&#8217;s why there is a method called &#8220;fear prevailing over joy&#8221; .The Scholars describes how Fan Jin goes into a delirium after he passes the provincial civil service examination under the old Chinese examination system. Because he is afraid of his father-in-law in peacetime, he recovers his mind after his father-in-law beats and scolds him. Although this is the plot of the novel, it is very suitable for the medical theory of fear prevailing over joy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">4. Joy Prevailing over Sorrow or Anxiety</h3>



<p>Anxiety belongs to lungs as much as sorrow. &#8220;Sorrow causing Qi consumption&#8221; refers to excessive sorrow would cause Qi consumption and dereliction of duty. In most cases, people feel sad because of the death of a friend or relative, setbacks, long illness, which often appear to be sad, depressed, crying for o reason, sighing, dejected and pessimistic, leading to a condition of gauntness. A doctor can use the things that patients like to listen to and are willing to see in order to make people in sad or anxiety smile again. That is the method of joy prevailing over sorrow or anxiety.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">5. Sorrow Prevailing over Anger</h3>



<p>Anger is controlled by liver. Rage causes transverse attack by liver Qi which means Qi and blood run upward together. From this, patient can have several symptoms such as irritability, flushed face, headache, dizziness, tinnitus, even hematemesis and fainting. Sorrow causing Qi consumption means anger can be suppressed and emotions can be restored. Therefore, there is a saying &#8220;sorrow prevailing over anger&#8221;. When the patients get angry, the doctor should try his best to comfort and persuade to move and cry, and eventually the anger can be released.</p>



<p>Investigations of Medical Prescriptions says that &#8220;Only drugs can not cure excessive emotional sensitivity, but Emotional Therapy is needed. After that, all dynasties have developed the theory of emotion in Internal Classic, which is an invisible medicine. If a good doctor can understand by analogy, he will master this technique.&#8221; In Confucian&#8217;s Duties to Parents, Zhang Zihe believes that “Sorrow can suppress anger. Doctors need to touch patients with sad words. Joy can suppress sorrow. Doctors should use humorous words to make patients laugh. Fear can suppress joy. Doctors should scare patients with horrible words. Anger suppresses</p>



<p>thought. Doctors should use words to provoke patients. Thought can suppress fear. Doctors should use words to worry the patient. All the five therapies must be applied craftily and weirdly so as to confuse the public. If the doctor has not learned the theory, he cannot use the five therapies. &#8220;Zhang&#8217;s explanation of the five emotions restricting therapy, especially the many examples in the book, reflects his ingenious conception and gives many inspirations to later doctors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Looping Therapy</h2>



<p>Looping therapy is put up with by Zhu Danxi,one of the four great scholars of Jin and Yuan dynasties. Besides, he supplements &#8220;the treatment by the generating ones&#8221;. Take the treatments of psychosis, mania and epilepsy diseases for example, Zhu Danxi emphasizes that these kinds of treatments couldn&#8217;t be pure use of medicinal stones, but must be accompanied by &#8220;the method of emotional intervention&#8221;. Therefore, he develops looping therapy with emotional intervention. He points out that &#8220;the manic and psychosis due to anger attacking liver can be controlled by anxiety and cured by fear; the psychosis and epilepsy caused by joy attacking heart can be controlled by fear and cured by anger; the epilepsy and psychosis due to anxiety attacking lung can be controlled by joy and cured by thought; the epilepsy and psychosis caused by thought attacking spleen can be controlled by anger and cured by joy; the psychosis resulted from fear attacking kidney can be controlled by thought and cured by anxiety; the psychosis due to freight attacking gallbladder can be controlled by anxiety and cured by fear; the psychosis caused by sorrow attacking pericardium can be controlled by fear and cured by anger.&#8221;(Medical Records from Danxi&#8217;s Experiential Therapy)Zhu&#8217;s looping therapy not only expands the restriction of five emotions from Internal Classic into restriction and domination of seven emotions, but also supplements the accompanying treatments of emotional stress remission by &#8220;the generating one&#8221; according to mother-son relationship, which make such treatments more flexible in clinical practice.</p>



<p>Sometimes, it may be a little far-fetching to regard the restriction of five phases as the treatment mechanism of emotions domination. However, emotional activities can be attributed to Yin or Yang in Yin-Yang theory, while from the modern psychological perspective, the emotional relationships can be differentiated by such polar characteristics (opposition) as anger and fear, joy and sorrow, fright and thought. Anger is attributed to Yang with its polar characteristic of Qi rising and flowing outward; fear is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi flowing downward and inward; joy is attributed to Yang with its polar characteristic of spirit dispersion; sorrow is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi blocking; fright is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi disturbing, which leads to palpitation, mental distraction and hesitation in making decisions; thought is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi stagnation. The Yin-Yang opposite relationship among emotions constitutes the contradictory relations physically and pathologically, leading to relative predominance and disorder of Yin or Yang in viscera, Qi and blood aspects. The basic principle of emotional restriction treatments is that the relative predominance of Yin and Yang due to emotional stress is controlled and restricted by its corresponding opposite one, which functions to balance the relationships between Yin and Yang, Qi and blood. Thus, a conclusion can be reached that anger dominates fear and is restricted conversely; joy dominates anxiety and is restricted adversely; fright dominates thought and is restricted on the contrary&#8230; Such polar opposite relationship by fully using of emotional activities, as a relative restriction and domination treatment, can make itself have greater development without the necessity of limitation of five phases.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clinical Application</h2>



<p>The emotional restriction treatment plays a better role than medicinal and other treatments in emotional stress remission, emotional diseases and various mental diseases caused by extreme emotions physically and pathologically. The emotional factors should not be ignored to the development, treatment, prognosis of disease, thus, this treatment can have corresponding effects in mental and physical diseases.</p>



<p>Yang Shangshan, the famous physician in Sui Dynasty, has some incisive opinions on the applications of this treatment. He notes in Grand Plain of Huangdi&#8217;s Internal Classic that &#8220;The diseases caused by wind, cold, summer heat, dampness, diets and intercourse can be treated by acupuncture and decoction; the treatments of emotional diseases must be combination of the emotion regulation, acupuncture and medicine&#8221;. Hence, the mental diseases should be treated psychologically at first by restriction of the extreme emotions, the physician should regulate patient&#8217;s emotions before using other accompanying treatments in the case of diseases involving other pathogenic factors.</p>



<p>It is the key point to manipulate the mental characteristics of the patient in this treatment. For instance, a rich woman suffers from insomnia for two years, which is immune to hundreds of treatments. Zhang Zihe diagnoses the disease as thought damaging spleen pattern according to her soft pulse. He irritates the woman to sweat, lie down and rest for several days by &#8220;applying the money to buy alcohol&#8221;, which is supposed to cure disease. At last, he cures that woman in this way (Confucians’ Duties to Parents). A scholar, living alone in a dark room, who is susceptible to fall ill in the case of occasional going out. Li Jianang, a physician in Qing Dynasty, cures this scholar with a set of herbs after reading his essay loudly and in a confused way deliberately to irritate him. (Medical Figures in Sichuan) The former case of anger restricting thought is based on the fact that the woman with narrow-minded and tightfisted mental status irritated by Zhang&#8217;s deliberate treating rejection; the latter one is based on the fact that the scholar with pretentious mental status irritated by Li&#8217;s deliberate essay misunderstanding. Take another case for example, a woman develops a disease after her husband go out for business for two years, which is characterized by anorexia, bed- ridden taciturnity and dementia. Zhu Danxi asks her father to irritate her by scolding and slapping her on the face, and then Zhu Danxi gives her spleen-activating medicine. At last, the woman begins to have some porridge after a set of formula, and then her disease is cured by joy from the fake coming-home message of her husband (Comments on Ancient and Modern Cases Records). The above three cases are all thought damaging spleen pattern. Physicians treat patient ingeniously according to the state of the illness and mental characteristic of the patient by using methods of anger restricting thought, accompanying treatment of formula and looping therapy. Therefore, it is necessary to apply this method according to pattern identification and treatment, and treatment in accordance with person, time and place.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attentions</h2>



<p>The treatment is not only applicable to remission of emotional stress, treatment of neurasthenia and hysteria, but also has some accompanying treating effects in psychopathy or morbid emotions. Those with weak constitutions or serious organic diseases should use with care.</p>



<p>The physician should observe and understand deeply about the patient&#8217;s living environment and mental characteristics, analyze carefully the cause of disease and abnormal mental reactions with combination of pathogenesis of viscera, Qi and blood, deficiency and repletion to get an appropriate treatment before applying the therapy.</p>



<p>The physician should be familiar with Yin-Yang and five phases theory of TCM, relations of mutual transformation between generation and restriction. It is also vital to assess the situation and have an inquiring mind for physician to cure disease with the treatment of emotional suppression.</p>



<p>The stimulus intensity should be noted during the treatment of emotional diseases, that is the therapeutic emotional stimulus usually exceeding the morbid ones, otherwise it is impossible to achieve the treatment effects of emotional suppression.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comments</h2>



<p>The principle and method of this therapy have distinctive TCM characteristics, which is lacking in modern psychology. If used appropriately, it can have miraculous treatment effects. It is helpful for the improvement of the treatment level of mental or physical diseases to research deeply and review systematically the rich clinical experiences of ancient famous physicians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essence and Qi Transfering Therapy</title>
		<link>https://chinesezodiac.org/p/essence-qi-transfering-therapy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 02:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Essence and Qi transfering therapy, also known as emotion-moving nature-changing therapy, refers to a psychotherapeutic method. During this process, the doctor uses various methods to transfer the mental activity of the patient so as to regulate and correct his movement of Qi disorder and other pathological conditions and help the patient recover from the illness.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Essence and Qi transfering therapy, also known as emotion-moving nature-changing therapy, refers to a psychotherapeutic method. During this process, the doctor uses various methods to transfer the mental activity of the patient so as to regulate and correct his movement of Qi disorder and other pathological conditions and help the patient recover from the illness.</p>



<p>Essence and Qi transfering is from Plain Questions: Discourse on Moving the Essence and Changing the Qi. It argues that &#8220;when the people in antiquity treated a disease,they simply moved the essence and changed the Qi&#8221; ,which emphasizes that this is a kind of treatment method widely used in clinic by ancient medical experts. Wang Bing of Tang Dynasty explains that &#8220;both moving and changing mean altering and they can make pathogenic factors not damage healthy Qi and keep the patient&#8217;s internal maintenance of essence and spirit within himself&#8221;. This explains that the therapy is a kind of recuperate medical care method, which achieves the therapeutic purpose by transferring or dispersing the patient&#8217;s spiritual thoughts. Gao Shizong of Qing Dynasty believes that &#8220;conduction means moving while inspiring means changing&#8221;, and explains that some methods, such as emotional conduction and spirit encouragement, can be used to change one&#8217;s mind and eliminate one&#8217;s obsessiveness from the perspective of treatment methods. Hua Xiuyun especially stresses that the cure for depression pattern is difficult to work out while summarizing Ye Tianshi&#8217;s experiences in treating depression pattern, &#8220;it all depends on the patient&#8217;s moving emotion and changing nature&#8221; (Case Records as a Guide to Clinical Practice).And Ye Tianshi suggests that the doctors should not only try to take medicinals of purgation and supplementation, but must be skillful in clinical reasoning to perform therapeutic effects.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Contents</h2>



<p>Guided by &#8220;the holism of body and spirit&#8221;, the therapy produces positive therapeutic effect by &#8220;curing the spirit and curing the body&#8221;. All the treatment methods that can play the role of moving emotion and changing nature can be applied flexibly according to the patient&#8217;s condition and psychological changes. Specific treatment methods can be roughly divided into emotion diversion and emotion conduction.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Emotion Diversion</h3>



<p>This method is one of the commonly used methods in clinical psychotherapy, that is, the mental activities of patients are transferred or dispersed from the focus of disease and worries to other aspects, so as to alleviate or eliminate the pathological changes caused by the malignant stimulation of these mental obsessiveness and promote the recovery of the disease.</p>



<p>Abnormal mental activities of patients are mainly manifested as follows. For general patients, especially those with introverted emotional personality and incurable diseases, their attention is more persistent on their own pain. Such as the fear of worsening disease, worry about the impact to work and life, suspected worry due to suffering from an incurable disease, or loss of confidence because of long-term treatment. In addition, due to the death of relatives and friends, setbacks in career, disappointment in love, financial distress and unexpected disasters, and other factors that lead to emotional depression, the patients are unable to extricate themselves. These excessive attention to their own suffering and strong emotional entanglements usually become the key to the long-term treatment of their diseases. If the patient does not try to distract the attention and transfer the negative emotional orientation to other aspects, even needles and medicinals will be ineffective.</p>



<p>There are many emotion diversion treatment methods. Besides Edificatory Speech therapy to relieve the patient&#8217;s psychological and emotional disorders (see &#8220;Edificatory Speech Therapy&#8221;), there are many other methods, such as the use of music, singing and dancing, lyre-playing, chess, calligraphy and painting, flower and bird, fishing, sightseeing and other methods to move emotion and change nature and play the role of smoothing the emotion and the movement of Qi. This is what Rhymed Discourse on External Remedies says, &#8220;for those with diseases of seven emotions, it is better to read and listen to music to relieve the loneliness and grief than to take medicine. &#8220;For example, The Book of Rites: The Book of Music has elaborated the influence of music on emotion in detail. When people hear bleak and low music, they will have sad feelings. When music has slow, lively, gorgeous, colorful and distinctive rhythm and other characteristics, it will make people produce serene and happy emotions. If music is magnificent and loud and full of passion, people will inspire resolute and exciting emotions. When people hear solemn music, they will have the feeling of serious reverence. When people hear soft, soothing and kind music, they will have a loving heart. Some quickly scattered perverse music will induce sexual feelings and so on. Therefore, Kong Yingda, a Confucian classics scholar of Tang Dynasty, points out: &#8220;the good and evil sounds of music originate from the hearts of the people. When you feel good, you respond well; when you feel bad, you react badly. The good and evil of music are from the hearts of the people at first and then the synthesis of music. Music is felt by people, good music is followed by people for good, bad music is followed by people for evil. Music is from people and also felt by people&#8221;. This shows that music not only exerts a subtle empathic effect on people&#8217;s emotions, but also cultivates people&#8217;s temperament and changes people&#8217;s behavior mode through the effect of music. The application of music in clinical treatment has been recorded in Zhou and Qin dynasties. It is said in Guan Zhong: Internal Industry: &#8220;The mortal life must live with balance, or the body will be attacked by abnormal joy, anger and sorrow. So, it is the reason to stop the anger by reciting pomes, and to removing sorrow by joys… Ancient medical doctors promoted music as one of the ways to modulate emotions and prevent diseases on that basis. Music, song and dance, drama,etc.,which are familiar by patients, all can be used as general emotion-moving means to adjust emotions; however, for some patients with severe mental disorders, they need to be treated by a treatment plan for their temperament type. For example, for patients with depression, they can relax their feelings with comics, funny things, comedy, etc. For those who are sad, they can listen to some idyllic music to ease their sentimental mood.</p>



<p>In addition, with the help of reading to be sensible, reciting to express feelings, calligraphy and paintings to be virtuous, fishing to cultivate one&#8217;s mind, touring to be refreshed etc., among which are beneficial to rehabilitation of physical and psychological diseases by moving emotions and cultivating dispositions. The ancient physicians use the &#8220;reading the righteousness book&#8221; as a way of self-cultivation, because the reading and reciting can not only be sensible, but also broaden the knowledge, and when it enters the artistic conception, it will have a certain therapeutic effect. A Sequel to Strange Tales by Qing Chengzi in Qing Dynasty states that &#8220;Zhu Gong in Baiyan suffers from an analgesic disease. When the disease occurs, he will recite a few poems of Du Fu to stop it, and it is useless to take medicine as timesgoes by. &#8220;When it comes to analyze the mechanism, the author points out: &#8220;Zhu Gong loves Du&#8217;s poems and if he reads his favorite pieces, his diseases will be alleviated.&#8221; Because &#8220;the patient&#8217;s disease is caused by obstruction of Qi, Du&#8217;s poems have varying intonation, therefore, it can lead to pain alleviation by Qi flourishing&#8221;.</p>



<p>The ancient doctors have accumulated rich experience in clinical trials with this method to treat various diseases, and left many clinical cases for future generations to study. OuYangxiu, a famous writer in Song Dynasty, suffered from severe depression. He was not cured by famous doctors. Later, he &#8220;studied the piano from Sun Youdao, and was inspired by the note of gong. Gradually he didn&#8217;t know his disease.&#8221; As far as its medical theory is concerned, gong is one of the five ancient tones, and it belongs to the spleen; the spleen dominates thought and thought can remove sorrow, so it is used to solve the problem with the note of gong. Marked by modern music, the note of gong is arranged in the scale of 1 (DO) in 12356; the melody of gong is dominated by the sound of gong, and it has a deep and simple style. For example, the ancient Chinese lyrics Moon on Guan Mountain is a five- sound gong style, which has a very strong appealing effect. OuYang Xiu not only deeply benefits from playing the piano to change temperament, but also through his experience, he says that he wants to calm his heart to treat his illness. He believes that playing the piano by &#8220;listening with ears and playing with hands can remove depressed feelings and alleviate sorrows.&#8221; His friend Yang Zhi was sick and depressed, and OuYang Xiu gave him a piano, telling him that it was better than using medicine to care for his feelings and distractions, and wrote Preface to Yang Zhi, in which his treatment experience was included. This is one of the examples of psychotherapy in ancient China.<br>Zhang Zihe, a famous doctor of Jin and Yuan dynasties, describes the case of Mr. Yang&#8217;s treatment of the diarrhea without the application of prescriptions in Confucians&#8217; Duties to Parents. He talks with the patient about the changes of the sun and the moon and the thunderstorms for seven or eight consecutive hours without hypnosis and the patient forgets to go to the toilet. Mr. Yang also tells Zhang Zihe:&#8221;The person who has diarrhea is treated by asking about his favorites. For example, a chess lover is treated by playing chess with him, a music fan is cured by playing the flute with him. &#8220;Zhang Zihe is also very good at using the form of music and singing and dancing to divert the attention of patients, and many similar medical cases are recorded in Confucians&#8217; Duties to Parents.<br>Yu Zhen, a famous doctor in Qing Dynasty, says that he suffers from nocturnal emission and hemoptysis due to lacking of caring and regulating when he is around fourteen and fifteen years old. He has nocturnal emission and seminal efflux for more than 10 times in a month when he is twenty-four years old. He has expectoration with blood and hectic fever frequently. At the time, although there is no improvement in treatment and his self- deprecation is definite fatal. After encountering a doctor, he is advised to read to cultivate his nature by the physician. Yu follows the instruction and devotes himself to exploring the book&#8217;s righteousness physically, which raises his great interest in book and the fear of death is gradually disappearing, and the pornographic dreams are no longer repeated and the mind state gradually clams down.&#8221;(Comments on Ancient and Modern Case Records).Reading is one of the main methods of ancient Confucian self-cultivation. This method not only has a strong subtle effect on the patient&#8217;s temperament, but also can produce a positive therapeutic effect by adjusting the state of the mind, and is also a means of empathy commonly used in modern medical methods.<br>Supplement to Classified Case Records of Famous Physicians records the case of the treatment of cataract by the famous doctor Yang Benheng of Ming Dynasty. It also reflects the effects of mental shift on the physiological and pathological state of the body. A noble person suffers from cataract, and his temperament becomes more and more violent. He takes mirror all day, and asks the famous doctor to diagnose and treat it, and his disease has no improvement. Yang says that his illness could be cured within days, however, drug poison has been accumulated in the left thigh due to overdoes, &#8220;it has been a critical state. &#8220;The noble turns to worry that his outbreak of poison and constantly gazes at his thigh and fondles it. Since then, the patient&#8217;s eye condition has gradually improved and the poison does not outbreak. After that, the patient asks about the reason, Yang says &#8220;it is physician&#8217;s intention to divert attention from eyes to thigh to reduce the mental fire&#8221;. In this case, the patient&#8217;s attention is transferred from the eye disease to the foot and thigh through psychological induction, which gives some time to perform self-spiritual adjustment, and even produces &#8220;shape&#8221; effects.<br>It can be seen that when these methods are applied into clinical cases to perform emotion moving, it is necessary to understand the patient&#8217;s hobbies, interests or causes firstly, and then to subtly determine which method is more suitable for the disease, and the focus of the application of this method.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Emotional Conduction Method</h3>



<p>Emotional conduction is a kind of treatment method by way of respiratory practice instructed by the physician or accompanying actions to control mental activity to attain the curing effect of shifting essence and changing Qi. The reason why it is called &#8220;emotional conduction&#8221; is that its aim to shift emotion and change nature is mainly by &#8220;conduction&#8221; (Qigong) rather than diverting or shifting the patient&#8217;s attention with the help of exterior things.</p>



<p>Qigong, the modern name, is called &#8220;conduction&#8221; &#8220;expiration and inspiration&#8221; &#8220;fetal respiration&#8221; &#8220;Qi regulation&#8221; by ancient health experts. It has formed a lot of schools and methods with penetrating and influencing of various traditional cultures and religions in its spreading history of thousands of years. When it comes to the most basic methods, namely, &#8220;heart regulation&#8221; (thought control), &#8220;Qi regulation&#8221; (breathing practice), &#8220;physical regulation&#8221; (position), and &#8220;thought&#8221; and &#8220;breathing&#8221; practice play a main role in emotional conduction method. It is concluded in Yun Ji Qi Jian that &#8220;treating my disease by regulating my emotion and Qi according to my physical status&#8221;, which reveals that Qigong highlights mind concentration and contemplation and regards thought self-control as top priority to gain the positive effects of body building and illness removing, by which stimulates channel Qi, dredges the meridian and regulates Qi and blood. Hence, Qigong is a kind of specific reflection of &#8220;essence shift and Qi transfer&#8221; in some way, which means that it eliminates such negative emotions as tension, anxiety and depression by regulating and controlling mental activities in order to gather genuine Qi by changing the direction and nature of psychological activities,(for example, turning blepharochalasis into internal concentration). Besides, with the instruction of thoughts and ideas, the vital Qi of human body gets stronger to resist pathogenic factors. Therefore, &#8220;essence shift&#8221; and &#8220;Qi transfer&#8221; are the basic effects generated by regulating human body both psychologically and physically.</p>



<p>The application of emotional conduction method, as it is said in Quotations of Life Nourishment, &#8220;deficiency disease is best by astringing thoughts and ideas to treat it; excess disease is best by massage to cure it; heat disease is best by smooth breathing to cool it; cold disease is best by rest and heating by fire to warm it. &#8220;The four methods, as short cuts of treatment, rein over such material medicines as herbs, metal and stone. The above is based on different diseases to perform treatments according to different patterns. For instance, the patient with deficient Yin and excessive Yang is treated by motionless methods; the patient with excessive Yin and deficient Yang is cured by active methods; the introvert one whose preference for motionless activity is better to do physical exercise activity and vice versa.</p>



<p>The &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221; can be applied in various of malevolent emotions caused by circumstance factors. Tao Hongjing, the famous scholar of the Northern and Southern Dynasty, says what quotes in Qi Sutra in Records of Nourishing Nature and Prolonging Life that, &#8220;blowing removes heat, exhaling eliminates wind, sighing removes irritability, breathing descends Qi, hissing dissolves stagnation, sobbing lifts extreme.&#8221;</p>



<p>The 44 conduction positions recorded from a roll of colored drawings in medical books of Han Dynasty were excavated from Mawangdui Tomb in Changsha in 1973,among which several conduction drawings and note texts showcase a kind of relation with &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221;. For example, one of drawing called &#8220;hate&#8221; depicts vividly a position performed by eyes gazing forward, lips closing slightly, hands straight, belly in and shoulder shrinkage in order to &#8220;exhale&#8221; the accumulated resentment slowly. It is proved to be a success by practice that performing such &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221; as &#8220;blowing, exhaling, sighing, breathing, hissing, sobbing &#8220;can remove visceral stagnant Qi such as irritability and tightness in chest to generate comfortable and relaxed senses. Other methods about emotional conduction can refer to corresponding treatments in Qigong and do not go into details.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clinical Application</h2>



<p>This method has double effects on psychological and physical regulation. Not only can it relieve emotional stress caused by various circumstance factors but also treat depressive disorder, neuroses, hysteria and other psychogenic or functional diseases. It can also treat lots of chronic diseases and have a good effect in treatment of organic disorders when applied properly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attentions</h2>



<p>The key to achieve treatment effects lies in absolute trust from patients. The patient has to give the physician absolute trust, follow the physician&#8217;s recommendations and coordinate the treatment, only in these ways can the treatment effect of emotion shift and nature change be achieved.</p>



<p>Although such methods as attracting, transferring and dispersing patients&#8217; attention can be applied as treatments, the uniqueness is that the patient is treated according to his/her illness, personality, emotion and the physician&#8217;s preference in a flexible way.</p>



<p>For those patients who are treated by emotional conduction method accompanied by Qigong practice, it is better to choose appropriate methods according to physicians&#8217; instructions, while hearsay and reckless acting are inadvisable.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comments</h2>



<p>The treatment of essence shift and Qi transfer has extensive meanings and effects in psychological health, psychotherapy based on medical practice and accumulated experience of thousands of years. In recent years, such therapies as music, art, calligraphy and painting, theater and drama have gained popularity overseas as the development of psychosomatic medicine. Besides, Modern Diagnostics and Therapeutics, the recently published book in America, underlines the importance of hobby transference and hobby or skill development, especially for those patients of the very idle. In addition, such a way has been approved and included in modern therapeutic concept, however, these therapies are mainly used in prophylaxis and treatment of situational of psychoses (such as melancholia and hysteria), since they are confined to psychanalysis and attention diversion. This therapy not only has obvious effect in psychogenic and functional disorders but also in organic and chronic diseases as an auxiliary method according to its rich and specific treatments both in mental adjustment and transference and Qigong practice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
