<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>KBL &#8211; Chinese Zodiac</title>
	<atom:link href="/p/author/kbl/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:02:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Emotion-suppression Therapy</title>
		<link>/p/emotion-suppression-therapy.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emotion-suppression therapy, a kind of psychological therapeutic method, is established under the guidance of theory of the five phases and restricting emotions. The therapy treats certain physical and mental ailments triggered by extreme emotions through restraining to remove the abnormal emotions. The theory and therapy concerning emotion-suppression first appear in Internal Classic. Being elaborated in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emotion-suppression therapy, a kind of psychological therapeutic method, is established under the guidance of theory of the five phases and restricting emotions. The therapy treats certain physical and mental ailments triggered by extreme emotions through restraining to remove the abnormal emotions.</p>



<p>The theory and therapy concerning emotion-suppression first appear in Internal Classic. Being elaborated in Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on Phenomena Corresponding to Yin and Yang, the emotions belong to five viscera and suppressing emotions (including &#8220;anger prevailing over thought&#8221; &#8220;thought prevailing over fear&#8221; &#8220;fear prevailing over joy&#8221; “joy prevailing over anxiety&#8221; &#8220;sorrow prevailing anger&#8221;), which are the rule of the five emotions that first appear in medical literature. Hereafter, being constantly supplemented and improved in terms of theory and clinical treatment, especially by Zhang Zihe, Zhu Danxi and other famous doctors in the Jin and Yuan dynasties, the therapy has become one of the main psychotherapies in TCM.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Contents</h2>



<p>Joy, anger, anxiety, thought, sorrow, fear and fright are called seven emotions in TCM. They&#8217;re the modal responses of people&#8217;s subjective feelings to external things. Ancient physicians attach great importance to the influence of emotional activities on the human body. In the course of long-term clinical observation, physicians realize that these modality reactions are intrinsically related to the visceral functions, and classify them with five viscera. In Internal Classic, joy is related to heart and belongs to fire; anger is related to liver and belongs to wood; anxiety (sorrow) is related to lung and belongs to metal; thought is related to spleen and belongs to the earth; fear is related to kidney and belongs to water. It is considered that human emotional activity is based on the essence of five viscera and is also one of the external manifestations of viscera. That is the connotation that&#8221; if five viscera are stable, blood vessel will run smoothly and the spirit will be eternal&#8221; in Spiritual Pivot: Fasting for Healthy People. If someone is suddenly subjected to intense mental stimulation or persistent mental trauma, his emotional activities will go beyond the scope of the body&#8217;s endurance and self-regulation, which will lead to the imbalance of Yin and Yang of the body, the inverse disorder of Qi and blood, and thereby impair the normal physiological functions of the viscera. The intense extreme emotion has its correlation and specificity on the impact of human visceral functions. Based on the damage of extreme emotion to human visceral activities, theories like &#8220;anger damaging liver&#8221; &#8220;joy damaging heart&#8221; &#8220;anxiety damaging spleen&#8221; &#8220;fear damaging kidney&#8221; &#8220;thought damaging spleen&#8221;, etc., are summarized by long-term clinical observation. At the same time, viscera give rise to pathological changes of deficiency and repletion which will generate abnormal emotional reactions of patients, such as &#8220;deficiency of heart Qi causing sorrow, while repletion causing consistent laughing&#8221;, &#8220;deficiency of liver Qi causing fear, while repletion causing anger&#8221;(Spiritual Pivot: Spirit-based Acupuncture), which is the sign of abnormal emotional changes of all viscera diseases.</p>



<p>The functions and activities of the viscera are closely related to each other. In order to maintain the physiological and psychological coordination and stability of the human body, the viscera are mutually generative and mutually restricting. This relationship is explained and reasoned by mutual generating and restraining among the five phases. In the theory of the five phases, the order of wood, fire, earth, metal and water are born one after another, which constitutes the promotion and generative relationship, and the lines of metal, wood, earth, water and fire are mutual restraining, which in turn constitutes the relationship of restraint and restriction. With the mutual generating and restraining between one thing and another, nature can be stable and unified; With the internal mutual generating and restraining of things, they can maintain coordination and development of themselves. Under the circumstance that extreme emotion damages the mental and physical homeostasis, physicians stimulate the phase being restricted to control the excess according to the five elements of emotions and their rules, so as to restore or reconstruct patients’ psychosomatic harmony, and achieve the purpose of treating the mental and physical diseases. Zhang Jingyue, a doctor of the Ming dynasty, emphasizes in the elaboration of emotion-suppression rules in Internal Classic that &#8220;if one of the five emotions is excessive, use the other to restrict it&#8221;, and he reveals the application basis and purpose of the therapy.</p>



<p>There are two treatments, the five emotions restricting therapy and looping therapy, which are described below.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Five Emotions Restricting Therapy</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. Anger Prevailing over Thought</h3>



<p>Thought is controlled by spleen and belongs to the earth. Thinking is a reflection of the process and ability of human beings to perceive things, which is not emotional in itself. People may feel anxious in that they are unable to understand or predict the outcome of an event. Therefore, in Internal Classic, &#8220;palpitation, thought and fright&#8221; and &#8220;anxiety and though&#8221; are described as one of the seven emotions. In daily life, excessive thinking caused by the things lingering in the heart or diligence often can cause symptoms of thought damaging spleen and dysfunction of spleen in transportation such as lack of appetite, abdominal fullness, and even anorexia, limb laziness. People who have been engaged in mental work for a long time suffer from insomnia, forgetfulness, palpitation and other signs</p>



<p>of mental nourishment failure due to excessive stress, which is believed in A-B Classic of Acupuncture and Moxibustion to be the cause of &#8220;thought comes from spleen and forms in heart&#8221;. Anger is liver&#8217;s emotion, and liver governs free coursing. Anger helps liver Qi rise, releasing bad emotions and rebuilding psychological balance. &#8220;Anger prevailing over thought&#8221; is the relationship of wood restraining earth from the perspective of the five phases. In terms of the physiological functions of the viscera, free coursing of liver Qi helps to activate spleen and release Qi. Therefore, in the clinical practice, methods such as deliberately disobeying the patient&#8217;s mind or taking away the patient&#8217;s beloved objects, etc. are often adopted to trigger his anger, so that the Qi can be released to the fullest extent, which can correct the pathological changes of &#8220;thought causing Qi stagnation&#8221;.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Thought Prevailing over Fear</h3>



<p>Fear is controlled by kidney and belongs to the water. It is a psychological reaction of the body, often associated with sudden shock, insecurity or fear in the face of an emergency or abnormal situation. Most of this fear will pass with time, and people need not worry about it. If people are exposed to a tense and fearful atmosphere for a long time, the body will always be in a state of stress, resulting in impaired physiological function. In severe cases, patients in sudden and continuous shock may have symptoms of &#8220;fear causing Qi sinking&#8221; such as urinary and fecal incontinence, seminal emission, efflux, diarrhea and so on. Patients often or persistently in fear will have restlessness, anxiety accompanied by the clinical symptoms of kidney damage and loss of essence, including bones and limbs weakness, thin and weak, even infertility so on. Treatment is often difficult to achieve by relying solely on medication without trying to free the patient from fear. Therefore, clinical treatment needs to be combined with psychological therapy like &#8220;thought prevailing over fear&#8217;. If the doctor can induce the patient to think according to the cause of fear and timidity, combining with the method of broadening their knowledge, strengthening their determination, thereby they can help patients gradually get rid of panic and fear.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. Fear Prevailing over Joy</h3>



<p>Joy is controlled by heart and belongs to the fire. &#8220;Joy causing Qi to slacken&#8221; mainly refers to the excessive joy will make people appear distracted, out of mind and spirit failing to keep to its abode. It is often characterized by an inability to concentrate, a trance, or even laughter in a state of madness. This kind of disease belongs to repletion pattern in that the treatment in clinic is mainly to clear heart and reduce fire. Fear causes timidity of Qi. If a doctor suddenly uses things that patients are usually afraid of to treat just like putting out fire with water, that&#8217;s why there is a method called &#8220;fear prevailing over joy&#8221; .The Scholars describes how Fan Jin goes into a delirium after he passes the provincial civil service examination under the old Chinese examination system. Because he is afraid of his father-in-law in peacetime, he recovers his mind after his father-in-law beats and scolds him. Although this is the plot of the novel, it is very suitable for the medical theory of fear prevailing over joy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">4. Joy Prevailing over Sorrow or Anxiety</h3>



<p>Anxiety belongs to lungs as much as sorrow. &#8220;Sorrow causing Qi consumption&#8221; refers to excessive sorrow would cause Qi consumption and dereliction of duty. In most cases, people feel sad because of the death of a friend or relative, setbacks, long illness, which often appear to be sad, depressed, crying for o reason, sighing, dejected and pessimistic, leading to a condition of gauntness. A doctor can use the things that patients like to listen to and are willing to see in order to make people in sad or anxiety smile again. That is the method of joy prevailing over sorrow or anxiety.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">5. Sorrow Prevailing over Anger</h3>



<p>Anger is controlled by liver. Rage causes transverse attack by liver Qi which means Qi and blood run upward together. From this, patient can have several symptoms such as irritability, flushed face, headache, dizziness, tinnitus, even hematemesis and fainting. Sorrow causing Qi consumption means anger can be suppressed and emotions can be restored. Therefore, there is a saying &#8220;sorrow prevailing over anger&#8221;. When the patients get angry, the doctor should try his best to comfort and persuade to move and cry, and eventually the anger can be released.</p>



<p>Investigations of Medical Prescriptions says that &#8220;Only drugs can not cure excessive emotional sensitivity, but Emotional Therapy is needed. After that, all dynasties have developed the theory of emotion in Internal Classic, which is an invisible medicine. If a good doctor can understand by analogy, he will master this technique.&#8221; In Confucian&#8217;s Duties to Parents, Zhang Zihe believes that “Sorrow can suppress anger. Doctors need to touch patients with sad words. Joy can suppress sorrow. Doctors should use humorous words to make patients laugh. Fear can suppress joy. Doctors should scare patients with horrible words. Anger suppresses</p>



<p>thought. Doctors should use words to provoke patients. Thought can suppress fear. Doctors should use words to worry the patient. All the five therapies must be applied craftily and weirdly so as to confuse the public. If the doctor has not learned the theory, he cannot use the five therapies. &#8220;Zhang&#8217;s explanation of the five emotions restricting therapy, especially the many examples in the book, reflects his ingenious conception and gives many inspirations to later doctors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Looping Therapy</h2>



<p>Looping therapy is put up with by Zhu Danxi,one of the four great scholars of Jin and Yuan dynasties. Besides, he supplements &#8220;the treatment by the generating ones&#8221;. Take the treatments of psychosis, mania and epilepsy diseases for example, Zhu Danxi emphasizes that these kinds of treatments couldn&#8217;t be pure use of medicinal stones, but must be accompanied by &#8220;the method of emotional intervention&#8221;. Therefore, he develops looping therapy with emotional intervention. He points out that &#8220;the manic and psychosis due to anger attacking liver can be controlled by anxiety and cured by fear; the psychosis and epilepsy caused by joy attacking heart can be controlled by fear and cured by anger; the epilepsy and psychosis due to anxiety attacking lung can be controlled by joy and cured by thought; the epilepsy and psychosis caused by thought attacking spleen can be controlled by anger and cured by joy; the psychosis resulted from fear attacking kidney can be controlled by thought and cured by anxiety; the psychosis due to freight attacking gallbladder can be controlled by anxiety and cured by fear; the psychosis caused by sorrow attacking pericardium can be controlled by fear and cured by anger.&#8221;(Medical Records from Danxi&#8217;s Experiential Therapy)Zhu&#8217;s looping therapy not only expands the restriction of five emotions from Internal Classic into restriction and domination of seven emotions, but also supplements the accompanying treatments of emotional stress remission by &#8220;the generating one&#8221; according to mother-son relationship, which make such treatments more flexible in clinical practice.</p>



<p>Sometimes, it may be a little far-fetching to regard the restriction of five phases as the treatment mechanism of emotions domination. However, emotional activities can be attributed to Yin or Yang in Yin-Yang theory, while from the modern psychological perspective, the emotional relationships can be differentiated by such polar characteristics (opposition) as anger and fear, joy and sorrow, fright and thought. Anger is attributed to Yang with its polar characteristic of Qi rising and flowing outward; fear is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi flowing downward and inward; joy is attributed to Yang with its polar characteristic of spirit dispersion; sorrow is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi blocking; fright is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi disturbing, which leads to palpitation, mental distraction and hesitation in making decisions; thought is attributed to Yin with its polar characteristic of Qi stagnation. The Yin-Yang opposite relationship among emotions constitutes the contradictory relations physically and pathologically, leading to relative predominance and disorder of Yin or Yang in viscera, Qi and blood aspects. The basic principle of emotional restriction treatments is that the relative predominance of Yin and Yang due to emotional stress is controlled and restricted by its corresponding opposite one, which functions to balance the relationships between Yin and Yang, Qi and blood. Thus, a conclusion can be reached that anger dominates fear and is restricted conversely; joy dominates anxiety and is restricted adversely; fright dominates thought and is restricted on the contrary&#8230; Such polar opposite relationship by fully using of emotional activities, as a relative restriction and domination treatment, can make itself have greater development without the necessity of limitation of five phases.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clinical Application</h2>



<p>The emotional restriction treatment plays a better role than medicinal and other treatments in emotional stress remission, emotional diseases and various mental diseases caused by extreme emotions physically and pathologically. The emotional factors should not be ignored to the development, treatment, prognosis of disease, thus, this treatment can have corresponding effects in mental and physical diseases.</p>



<p>Yang Shangshan, the famous physician in Sui Dynasty, has some incisive opinions on the applications of this treatment. He notes in Grand Plain of Huangdi&#8217;s Internal Classic that &#8220;The diseases caused by wind, cold, summer heat, dampness, diets and intercourse can be treated by acupuncture and decoction; the treatments of emotional diseases must be combination of the emotion regulation, acupuncture and medicine&#8221;. Hence, the mental diseases should be treated psychologically at first by restriction of the extreme emotions, the physician should regulate patient&#8217;s emotions before using other accompanying treatments in the case of diseases involving other pathogenic factors.</p>



<p>It is the key point to manipulate the mental characteristics of the patient in this treatment. For instance, a rich woman suffers from insomnia for two years, which is immune to hundreds of treatments. Zhang Zihe diagnoses the disease as thought damaging spleen pattern according to her soft pulse. He irritates the woman to sweat, lie down and rest for several days by &#8220;applying the money to buy alcohol&#8221;, which is supposed to cure disease. At last, he cures that woman in this way (Confucians’ Duties to Parents). A scholar, living alone in a dark room, who is susceptible to fall ill in the case of occasional going out. Li Jianang, a physician in Qing Dynasty, cures this scholar with a set of herbs after reading his essay loudly and in a confused way deliberately to irritate him. (Medical Figures in Sichuan) The former case of anger restricting thought is based on the fact that the woman with narrow-minded and tightfisted mental status irritated by Zhang&#8217;s deliberate treating rejection; the latter one is based on the fact that the scholar with pretentious mental status irritated by Li&#8217;s deliberate essay misunderstanding. Take another case for example, a woman develops a disease after her husband go out for business for two years, which is characterized by anorexia, bed- ridden taciturnity and dementia. Zhu Danxi asks her father to irritate her by scolding and slapping her on the face, and then Zhu Danxi gives her spleen-activating medicine. At last, the woman begins to have some porridge after a set of formula, and then her disease is cured by joy from the fake coming-home message of her husband (Comments on Ancient and Modern Cases Records). The above three cases are all thought damaging spleen pattern. Physicians treat patient ingeniously according to the state of the illness and mental characteristic of the patient by using methods of anger restricting thought, accompanying treatment of formula and looping therapy. Therefore, it is necessary to apply this method according to pattern identification and treatment, and treatment in accordance with person, time and place.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attentions</h2>



<p>The treatment is not only applicable to remission of emotional stress, treatment of neurasthenia and hysteria, but also has some accompanying treating effects in psychopathy or morbid emotions. Those with weak constitutions or serious organic diseases should use with care.</p>



<p>The physician should observe and understand deeply about the patient&#8217;s living environment and mental characteristics, analyze carefully the cause of disease and abnormal mental reactions with combination of pathogenesis of viscera, Qi and blood, deficiency and repletion to get an appropriate treatment before applying the therapy.</p>



<p>The physician should be familiar with Yin-Yang and five phases theory of TCM, relations of mutual transformation between generation and restriction. It is also vital to assess the situation and have an inquiring mind for physician to cure disease with the treatment of emotional suppression.</p>



<p>The stimulus intensity should be noted during the treatment of emotional diseases, that is the therapeutic emotional stimulus usually exceeding the morbid ones, otherwise it is impossible to achieve the treatment effects of emotional suppression.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comments</h2>



<p>The principle and method of this therapy have distinctive TCM characteristics, which is lacking in modern psychology. If used appropriately, it can have miraculous treatment effects. It is helpful for the improvement of the treatment level of mental or physical diseases to research deeply and review systematically the rich clinical experiences of ancient famous physicians.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Essence and Qi Transfering Therapy</title>
		<link>/p/essence-qi-transfering-therapy.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 02:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Essence and Qi transfering therapy, also known as emotion-moving nature-changing therapy, refers to a psychotherapeutic method. During this process, the doctor uses various methods to transfer the mental activity of the patient so as to regulate and correct his movement of Qi disorder and other pathological conditions and help the patient recover from the illness.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Essence and Qi transfering therapy, also known as emotion-moving nature-changing therapy, refers to a psychotherapeutic method. During this process, the doctor uses various methods to transfer the mental activity of the patient so as to regulate and correct his movement of Qi disorder and other pathological conditions and help the patient recover from the illness.</p>



<p>Essence and Qi transfering is from Plain Questions: Discourse on Moving the Essence and Changing the Qi. It argues that &#8220;when the people in antiquity treated a disease,they simply moved the essence and changed the Qi&#8221; ,which emphasizes that this is a kind of treatment method widely used in clinic by ancient medical experts. Wang Bing of Tang Dynasty explains that &#8220;both moving and changing mean altering and they can make pathogenic factors not damage healthy Qi and keep the patient&#8217;s internal maintenance of essence and spirit within himself&#8221;. This explains that the therapy is a kind of recuperate medical care method, which achieves the therapeutic purpose by transferring or dispersing the patient&#8217;s spiritual thoughts. Gao Shizong of Qing Dynasty believes that &#8220;conduction means moving while inspiring means changing&#8221;, and explains that some methods, such as emotional conduction and spirit encouragement, can be used to change one&#8217;s mind and eliminate one&#8217;s obsessiveness from the perspective of treatment methods. Hua Xiuyun especially stresses that the cure for depression pattern is difficult to work out while summarizing Ye Tianshi&#8217;s experiences in treating depression pattern, &#8220;it all depends on the patient&#8217;s moving emotion and changing nature&#8221; (Case Records as a Guide to Clinical Practice).And Ye Tianshi suggests that the doctors should not only try to take medicinals of purgation and supplementation, but must be skillful in clinical reasoning to perform therapeutic effects.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Contents</h2>



<p>Guided by &#8220;the holism of body and spirit&#8221;, the therapy produces positive therapeutic effect by &#8220;curing the spirit and curing the body&#8221;. All the treatment methods that can play the role of moving emotion and changing nature can be applied flexibly according to the patient&#8217;s condition and psychological changes. Specific treatment methods can be roughly divided into emotion diversion and emotion conduction.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Emotion Diversion</h3>



<p>This method is one of the commonly used methods in clinical psychotherapy, that is, the mental activities of patients are transferred or dispersed from the focus of disease and worries to other aspects, so as to alleviate or eliminate the pathological changes caused by the malignant stimulation of these mental obsessiveness and promote the recovery of the disease.</p>



<p>Abnormal mental activities of patients are mainly manifested as follows. For general patients, especially those with introverted emotional personality and incurable diseases, their attention is more persistent on their own pain. Such as the fear of worsening disease, worry about the impact to work and life, suspected worry due to suffering from an incurable disease, or loss of confidence because of long-term treatment. In addition, due to the death of relatives and friends, setbacks in career, disappointment in love, financial distress and unexpected disasters, and other factors that lead to emotional depression, the patients are unable to extricate themselves. These excessive attention to their own suffering and strong emotional entanglements usually become the key to the long-term treatment of their diseases. If the patient does not try to distract the attention and transfer the negative emotional orientation to other aspects, even needles and medicinals will be ineffective.</p>



<p>There are many emotion diversion treatment methods. Besides Edificatory Speech therapy to relieve the patient&#8217;s psychological and emotional disorders (see &#8220;Edificatory Speech Therapy&#8221;), there are many other methods, such as the use of music, singing and dancing, lyre-playing, chess, calligraphy and painting, flower and bird, fishing, sightseeing and other methods to move emotion and change nature and play the role of smoothing the emotion and the movement of Qi. This is what Rhymed Discourse on External Remedies says, &#8220;for those with diseases of seven emotions, it is better to read and listen to music to relieve the loneliness and grief than to take medicine. &#8220;For example, The Book of Rites: The Book of Music has elaborated the influence of music on emotion in detail. When people hear bleak and low music, they will have sad feelings. When music has slow, lively, gorgeous, colorful and distinctive rhythm and other characteristics, it will make people produce serene and happy emotions. If music is magnificent and loud and full of passion, people will inspire resolute and exciting emotions. When people hear solemn music, they will have the feeling of serious reverence. When people hear soft, soothing and kind music, they will have a loving heart. Some quickly scattered perverse music will induce sexual feelings and so on. Therefore, Kong Yingda, a Confucian classics scholar of Tang Dynasty, points out: &#8220;the good and evil sounds of music originate from the hearts of the people. When you feel good, you respond well; when you feel bad, you react badly. The good and evil of music are from the hearts of the people at first and then the synthesis of music. Music is felt by people, good music is followed by people for good, bad music is followed by people for evil. Music is from people and also felt by people&#8221;. This shows that music not only exerts a subtle empathic effect on people&#8217;s emotions, but also cultivates people&#8217;s temperament and changes people&#8217;s behavior mode through the effect of music. The application of music in clinical treatment has been recorded in Zhou and Qin dynasties. It is said in Guan Zhong: Internal Industry: &#8220;The mortal life must live with balance, or the body will be attacked by abnormal joy, anger and sorrow. So, it is the reason to stop the anger by reciting pomes, and to removing sorrow by joys… Ancient medical doctors promoted music as one of the ways to modulate emotions and prevent diseases on that basis. Music, song and dance, drama,etc.,which are familiar by patients, all can be used as general emotion-moving means to adjust emotions; however, for some patients with severe mental disorders, they need to be treated by a treatment plan for their temperament type. For example, for patients with depression, they can relax their feelings with comics, funny things, comedy, etc. For those who are sad, they can listen to some idyllic music to ease their sentimental mood.</p>



<p>In addition, with the help of reading to be sensible, reciting to express feelings, calligraphy and paintings to be virtuous, fishing to cultivate one&#8217;s mind, touring to be refreshed etc., among which are beneficial to rehabilitation of physical and psychological diseases by moving emotions and cultivating dispositions. The ancient physicians use the &#8220;reading the righteousness book&#8221; as a way of self-cultivation, because the reading and reciting can not only be sensible, but also broaden the knowledge, and when it enters the artistic conception, it will have a certain therapeutic effect. A Sequel to Strange Tales by Qing Chengzi in Qing Dynasty states that &#8220;Zhu Gong in Baiyan suffers from an analgesic disease. When the disease occurs, he will recite a few poems of Du Fu to stop it, and it is useless to take medicine as timesgoes by. &#8220;When it comes to analyze the mechanism, the author points out: &#8220;Zhu Gong loves Du&#8217;s poems and if he reads his favorite pieces, his diseases will be alleviated.&#8221; Because &#8220;the patient&#8217;s disease is caused by obstruction of Qi, Du&#8217;s poems have varying intonation, therefore, it can lead to pain alleviation by Qi flourishing&#8221;.</p>



<p>The ancient doctors have accumulated rich experience in clinical trials with this method to treat various diseases, and left many clinical cases for future generations to study. OuYangxiu, a famous writer in Song Dynasty, suffered from severe depression. He was not cured by famous doctors. Later, he &#8220;studied the piano from Sun Youdao, and was inspired by the note of gong. Gradually he didn&#8217;t know his disease.&#8221; As far as its medical theory is concerned, gong is one of the five ancient tones, and it belongs to the spleen; the spleen dominates thought and thought can remove sorrow, so it is used to solve the problem with the note of gong. Marked by modern music, the note of gong is arranged in the scale of 1 (DO) in 12356; the melody of gong is dominated by the sound of gong, and it has a deep and simple style. For example, the ancient Chinese lyrics Moon on Guan Mountain is a five- sound gong style, which has a very strong appealing effect. OuYang Xiu not only deeply benefits from playing the piano to change temperament, but also through his experience, he says that he wants to calm his heart to treat his illness. He believes that playing the piano by &#8220;listening with ears and playing with hands can remove depressed feelings and alleviate sorrows.&#8221; His friend Yang Zhi was sick and depressed, and OuYang Xiu gave him a piano, telling him that it was better than using medicine to care for his feelings and distractions, and wrote Preface to Yang Zhi, in which his treatment experience was included. This is one of the examples of psychotherapy in ancient China.<br>Zhang Zihe, a famous doctor of Jin and Yuan dynasties, describes the case of Mr. Yang&#8217;s treatment of the diarrhea without the application of prescriptions in Confucians&#8217; Duties to Parents. He talks with the patient about the changes of the sun and the moon and the thunderstorms for seven or eight consecutive hours without hypnosis and the patient forgets to go to the toilet. Mr. Yang also tells Zhang Zihe:&#8221;The person who has diarrhea is treated by asking about his favorites. For example, a chess lover is treated by playing chess with him, a music fan is cured by playing the flute with him. &#8220;Zhang Zihe is also very good at using the form of music and singing and dancing to divert the attention of patients, and many similar medical cases are recorded in Confucians&#8217; Duties to Parents.<br>Yu Zhen, a famous doctor in Qing Dynasty, says that he suffers from nocturnal emission and hemoptysis due to lacking of caring and regulating when he is around fourteen and fifteen years old. He has nocturnal emission and seminal efflux for more than 10 times in a month when he is twenty-four years old. He has expectoration with blood and hectic fever frequently. At the time, although there is no improvement in treatment and his self- deprecation is definite fatal. After encountering a doctor, he is advised to read to cultivate his nature by the physician. Yu follows the instruction and devotes himself to exploring the book&#8217;s righteousness physically, which raises his great interest in book and the fear of death is gradually disappearing, and the pornographic dreams are no longer repeated and the mind state gradually clams down.&#8221;(Comments on Ancient and Modern Case Records).Reading is one of the main methods of ancient Confucian self-cultivation. This method not only has a strong subtle effect on the patient&#8217;s temperament, but also can produce a positive therapeutic effect by adjusting the state of the mind, and is also a means of empathy commonly used in modern medical methods.<br>Supplement to Classified Case Records of Famous Physicians records the case of the treatment of cataract by the famous doctor Yang Benheng of Ming Dynasty. It also reflects the effects of mental shift on the physiological and pathological state of the body. A noble person suffers from cataract, and his temperament becomes more and more violent. He takes mirror all day, and asks the famous doctor to diagnose and treat it, and his disease has no improvement. Yang says that his illness could be cured within days, however, drug poison has been accumulated in the left thigh due to overdoes, &#8220;it has been a critical state. &#8220;The noble turns to worry that his outbreak of poison and constantly gazes at his thigh and fondles it. Since then, the patient&#8217;s eye condition has gradually improved and the poison does not outbreak. After that, the patient asks about the reason, Yang says &#8220;it is physician&#8217;s intention to divert attention from eyes to thigh to reduce the mental fire&#8221;. In this case, the patient&#8217;s attention is transferred from the eye disease to the foot and thigh through psychological induction, which gives some time to perform self-spiritual adjustment, and even produces &#8220;shape&#8221; effects.<br>It can be seen that when these methods are applied into clinical cases to perform emotion moving, it is necessary to understand the patient&#8217;s hobbies, interests or causes firstly, and then to subtly determine which method is more suitable for the disease, and the focus of the application of this method.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Emotional Conduction Method</h3>



<p>Emotional conduction is a kind of treatment method by way of respiratory practice instructed by the physician or accompanying actions to control mental activity to attain the curing effect of shifting essence and changing Qi. The reason why it is called &#8220;emotional conduction&#8221; is that its aim to shift emotion and change nature is mainly by &#8220;conduction&#8221; (Qigong) rather than diverting or shifting the patient&#8217;s attention with the help of exterior things.</p>



<p>Qigong, the modern name, is called &#8220;conduction&#8221; &#8220;expiration and inspiration&#8221; &#8220;fetal respiration&#8221; &#8220;Qi regulation&#8221; by ancient health experts. It has formed a lot of schools and methods with penetrating and influencing of various traditional cultures and religions in its spreading history of thousands of years. When it comes to the most basic methods, namely, &#8220;heart regulation&#8221; (thought control), &#8220;Qi regulation&#8221; (breathing practice), &#8220;physical regulation&#8221; (position), and &#8220;thought&#8221; and &#8220;breathing&#8221; practice play a main role in emotional conduction method. It is concluded in Yun Ji Qi Jian that &#8220;treating my disease by regulating my emotion and Qi according to my physical status&#8221;, which reveals that Qigong highlights mind concentration and contemplation and regards thought self-control as top priority to gain the positive effects of body building and illness removing, by which stimulates channel Qi, dredges the meridian and regulates Qi and blood. Hence, Qigong is a kind of specific reflection of &#8220;essence shift and Qi transfer&#8221; in some way, which means that it eliminates such negative emotions as tension, anxiety and depression by regulating and controlling mental activities in order to gather genuine Qi by changing the direction and nature of psychological activities,(for example, turning blepharochalasis into internal concentration). Besides, with the instruction of thoughts and ideas, the vital Qi of human body gets stronger to resist pathogenic factors. Therefore, &#8220;essence shift&#8221; and &#8220;Qi transfer&#8221; are the basic effects generated by regulating human body both psychologically and physically.</p>



<p>The application of emotional conduction method, as it is said in Quotations of Life Nourishment, &#8220;deficiency disease is best by astringing thoughts and ideas to treat it; excess disease is best by massage to cure it; heat disease is best by smooth breathing to cool it; cold disease is best by rest and heating by fire to warm it. &#8220;The four methods, as short cuts of treatment, rein over such material medicines as herbs, metal and stone. The above is based on different diseases to perform treatments according to different patterns. For instance, the patient with deficient Yin and excessive Yang is treated by motionless methods; the patient with excessive Yin and deficient Yang is cured by active methods; the introvert one whose preference for motionless activity is better to do physical exercise activity and vice versa.</p>



<p>The &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221; can be applied in various of malevolent emotions caused by circumstance factors. Tao Hongjing, the famous scholar of the Northern and Southern Dynasty, says what quotes in Qi Sutra in Records of Nourishing Nature and Prolonging Life that, &#8220;blowing removes heat, exhaling eliminates wind, sighing removes irritability, breathing descends Qi, hissing dissolves stagnation, sobbing lifts extreme.&#8221;</p>



<p>The 44 conduction positions recorded from a roll of colored drawings in medical books of Han Dynasty were excavated from Mawangdui Tomb in Changsha in 1973,among which several conduction drawings and note texts showcase a kind of relation with &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221;. For example, one of drawing called &#8220;hate&#8221; depicts vividly a position performed by eyes gazing forward, lips closing slightly, hands straight, belly in and shoulder shrinkage in order to &#8220;exhale&#8221; the accumulated resentment slowly. It is proved to be a success by practice that performing such &#8220;six words of Qi&#8221; as &#8220;blowing, exhaling, sighing, breathing, hissing, sobbing &#8220;can remove visceral stagnant Qi such as irritability and tightness in chest to generate comfortable and relaxed senses. Other methods about emotional conduction can refer to corresponding treatments in Qigong and do not go into details.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clinical Application</h2>



<p>This method has double effects on psychological and physical regulation. Not only can it relieve emotional stress caused by various circumstance factors but also treat depressive disorder, neuroses, hysteria and other psychogenic or functional diseases. It can also treat lots of chronic diseases and have a good effect in treatment of organic disorders when applied properly.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attentions</h2>



<p>The key to achieve treatment effects lies in absolute trust from patients. The patient has to give the physician absolute trust, follow the physician&#8217;s recommendations and coordinate the treatment, only in these ways can the treatment effect of emotion shift and nature change be achieved.</p>



<p>Although such methods as attracting, transferring and dispersing patients&#8217; attention can be applied as treatments, the uniqueness is that the patient is treated according to his/her illness, personality, emotion and the physician&#8217;s preference in a flexible way.</p>



<p>For those patients who are treated by emotional conduction method accompanied by Qigong practice, it is better to choose appropriate methods according to physicians&#8217; instructions, while hearsay and reckless acting are inadvisable.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comments</h2>



<p>The treatment of essence shift and Qi transfer has extensive meanings and effects in psychological health, psychotherapy based on medical practice and accumulated experience of thousands of years. In recent years, such therapies as music, art, calligraphy and painting, theater and drama have gained popularity overseas as the development of psychosomatic medicine. Besides, Modern Diagnostics and Therapeutics, the recently published book in America, underlines the importance of hobby transference and hobby or skill development, especially for those patients of the very idle. In addition, such a way has been approved and included in modern therapeutic concept, however, these therapies are mainly used in prophylaxis and treatment of situational of psychoses (such as melancholia and hysteria), since they are confined to psychanalysis and attention diversion. This therapy not only has obvious effect in psychogenic and functional disorders but also in organic and chronic diseases as an auxiliary method according to its rich and specific treatments both in mental adjustment and transference and Qigong practice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edificatory Speech Therapy</title>
		<link>/p/edificatory-speech-therapy.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 16:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edificatory speech therapy is a kind of psychotherapy that uses the language to talk about the patient's condition and its psychological state, affective disorder, etc. ,to eliminate the cause of the disease and correct its adverse emotions and emotional activities. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Edificatory speech therapy is a kind of psychotherapy that uses the language to talk about the patient&#8217;s condition and its psychological state, affective disorder, etc. ,to eliminate the cause of the disease and correct its adverse emotions and emotional activities. Spiritual Pivot: Instructions of the Teacher points out: &#8220;It is human to dislike death and prefer living. The doctor should tell the patients what are harmful to their health, let them know what are good for their health, guide them to do what they like for storing their health and try to straighten them out of their anxiety. If the doctor has done all that is required, even a most unreasonable person will follow his advice. &#8220;The treatment and mechanisms of this therapy are explained in principle.</p>



<p>The therapy can be traced back to the ancient times. Plain Questions: Discourse on Moving the Essence and Changing he Qi says: &#8220;When the people in antiquity treated a disease, they simply moved the essence and changed the Qi. They were able to invoke the origin and any disease came to an end. &#8220;It is a psychotherapy &#8220;to invoke origin without need of needles and pointed stones&#8221; (Wang Bing&#8217;s notes). As for invoking origin, Spiritual Pivot: Thief- like Wind interprets it as &#8220;Sorcerers in ancient times knew the causes and treatments of diseases. What they usually did was to find out the cause of a disease first and then treated it by prayers.&#8221; Zhang Jingyue, a doctor of Ming Dynasty, believes that invoking origin is a special treatment with conversation and different from the superstition of the spell. lt works through the doctor&#8217;s &#8220;searching for the cause of the disease and releasing the &#8216;ghost&#8217; in heart&#8221;. The common methods include &#8220;guidance and persuasion&#8221;, &#8220;disambiguation and distinguishing right&#8221;, and so on. Since Tang Dynasty, there are departments of invoking origin set up in many hospitals in the past and there are medical officers in charge. Invoking origin is similar to modern psychotherapy if some of its superstitious elements and mysterious colors are removed. Therefore, Edificatory Speech therapy has important clinical value.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Basic Contents</h2>



<p>Language conversation is not only the main emotional medium for communication between people, but also the basic way to understand and master the psychological and emotional activities of patients, and the basic premise of applying edificatory speech. Spiritual Pivot: Qualifications of Acupuncturists says: &#8220;People with eloquence can be assigned the duty of discussing theory. &#8220;The so-called &#8220;eloquence&#8221; refers to the ability to express. Psychotherapists, especially those with the use of this therapy and the ability, must master the theory of TCM and psychological and behavioral analysis methods in order to adopt appropriate conversation methods and techniques based on the patient&#8217;s temperament type and psychological and emotional disorders. Through the analysis of the disease, they tell patients the causes, consequences and harm of the disease, persuade patients to correct bad habits, eliminate the fear, pessimism, depression and other moods that hinder rehabilitation, and guide patients to rationally choose the good rehabilitation method to the body and mind, so as to obtain a satisfactory psychological treatment. This is the basic spirit of &#8220;tell&#8221;, &#8220;let them know&#8221;, &#8220;guide&#8221; and &#8220;straighten&#8221; elaborated in Spiritual Pivot: Instructions of the Teacher, and also the main principle and method used in the application of the edificatory speech therapy.</p>



<p>In the clinical diagnosis and treatment process, the patient&#8217;s physical conditions and temperament type should be observed and analyzed first. Qi Shi, a doctor of Ming Dynasty, points out in Primary Mirror of Rectifying Deficiency: &#8220;The human endowments are different and the causes of diseases are different. &#8220;The endowment he mentions mainly refers to the individual temperament characteristics of the patient, emphasizing the different susceptibility of people with different physical conditions and temperament types. TCM attaches great importance to different types of personality psychological characteristics (including emotion, personality, will, ability, etc.) and their relationship with disease. Since Internal Classic, there has been complete and systematic discussion of the classification of individual physical and mental characteristics. For example, Spiritual Pivot: Correspondence between Man and Nature divides the crowd into five types: greater Yang, lesser Yang, greater Yin, lesser Yin as well as balanced Yin and Yang, according to the quantity of Yin and Yang. Spiritual Pivot: Twenty-five Types of People Divided According to Yin and Yang summarizes the physical and mental characteristics of metal, wood, water, fire and earth people from the perspective of five phases. Based on this and together with predominance of five phases, it subdivides into twenty-five sub-types, and describes in detail the emotional, cognitional, will, behavioral and other psychological characteristics and physical features such as head, limbs, trunk, skin color, sound, etc., as well as even the susceptible diseases, timing, pathogenesis, treatment and other clinical characteristics of various types of people. For example, greater Yang (fire) people generally show small head, thin cheek, full shoulder and red complexion. Their behaviors are often expressed as self-use, quick and decisive, sometimes putting into action without consideration, often revealing a self-satisfied or arrogant attitude, which reflects impatience, impulsiveness, self-esteem and other extroversion characteristics of greater Yang (fire)people. The physical appearance, demeanor and behavior of greater Yin (water) people are generally humble, introversive, considerate, determined before action, even deceptive and other introverted psychological characteristics (table 2-1).These discourses of Internal Classic have become the main basis for future generations of doctors to conduct psychological and behavioral analysis of patients and to guide the clinical use of edificatory speech therapy.</p>



<p>The patient&#8217;s emotional extremes can also be caused by malignant stimulation of factors such as the situation, and become one of the original causes of many internal injuries. Therefore, it is the key to the effectiveness of this therapy to examine the patient&#8217;s emotional changes and enlighten him according to his temperament. The doctors of previous generations repeatedly state that the patient&#8217;s onset of the disease must be carefully consulted before comprehensively understanding his social experiences, living habits, hobbies, personnel changes, etc. and grasping his emotional activities such as joy, anger, sorrow and happiness. It is &#8220;to find out the cause of a disease first&#8221; and then dispel the cause of the disease and relieve his mental burden. For many patients, Primary Mirror of Rectifying Deficiency points out: &#8220;those of temperamental predominance and unable to balance their spirits should be treated their temperament; those of immoderate lust should control desire to nourish essence; those stagnant in mood should control annoyance to nourish spirit; those irritating and unreasonable should control anger to nourish liver; those impetuous should control hard work to nourish strength; those thoughtful should control thought to nourish heart; those compassionate should control sorrow to nourish lung. &#8220;Therefore, for the treatment, the doctor should fully exert his influence on the patient and play the role of Edificatory speech therapy. &#8220;Alert of life and death&#8221; or &#8220;right with morality and justice&#8221; or &#8220;guide be free and easy&#8221; or clear up doubts or remove the wild fancy or tell bluntly or reason allegorically, so as to &#8220;debind and open the glue &#8220;to relieve the patient&#8217;s mental and physical pains. For doctors, when applying these methods, only when &#8220;diseases met the right doctor can the affect between them be achieved and the diseases be cured&#8221;. (Classified Classic) It is difficult to work if the affect between doctors and patients cannot be achieved. Therefore, Zhang Jiebin emphasizes that &#8220;discipline being not strict cannot suppress the desire; speeches being not sincere cannot change the spirit&#8221;. These principles and treatments elaborated by the ancient physicians have general guiding significance for the clinical application of this therapy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td colspan="7">Table 2-1 Classification Table of Physical and Mental Characteristics in Internal Classic</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" rowspan="2">Characteristics</td><td colspan="5">Category</td></tr><tr><td>people with greater Yang (fire)</td><td>people with lesser Yang (metal)</td><td>people with balanced Yin and Yang (earth)</td><td>people with lesser Yin (wood)</td><td>people with greater Yin (water)</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2">Physiological characteristics</td><td>exuberance of Yang with decline of Yin</td><td>exuberance of Yang with lesser Yin</td><td>balanced Yin and Yang</td><td>exuberance of Yin with lesser Yang</td><td>exuberance of Yin with decline of Yang</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="6">Psychological characteristics</td><td>Emotion</td><td>impatient, impulsive, good at resolving sorrows and worries, optimistic and open- minded, comfortable and self-satisfied</td><td>impatient, firm and refreshing, vain</td><td>frank, peaceful, happy and cheerful, fearless</td><td>introverted, silent, sentimental, jealous</td><td>introverted, self-abased, or stubborn, or deceptive, or emotionless, or quiet as water, indifferent</td></tr><tr><td>Cognition</td><td>good at observation and thinking, quick at response, conclusive only based on the superficial phenomenon, superficial in understanding</td><td>in-depth and prudent in observing and understanding objective things, clear about what is right and wrong, of management skills, arrogant</td><td>obedient to the law of the development, grasping the essence, able to adapt to the situation, of high level. of understanding and management skills</td><td>scheming, diligent in thinking, smart and intelligent, of high level of cognition and the ability to engage in mental work</td><td>not readily publishing and changing own ideas, good at listening to other people&#8217;s opinions, slow in cognitive speed but high in cognitive quality, profound scrutiny of problems</td></tr><tr><td>Will</td><td>emulative, self-willed, bold, rash, no regret even if failure, unrealistic, starting without end</td><td>firm, not dependent on people, of strong self-control and will</td><td>strong-willed, independent, dedicated, not afraid of hardships, not self-willed, sometimes flexible and following</td><td>indecisive in will, easy going, or concessive, or idle, or enterprising in career</td><td>weak in will, taking action following the actions of most people on the basis of repeated thoughts</td></tr><tr><td>Behavior</td><td>treating people honestly, good at socializing will to make friends, paying a little attention to money; rude in behavior, impulsive, flatulent, gassy, lack of credit; adapting to the surrounding environment quickly</td><td>good at diplomacy, entertainment 1 and social activities; honest and fair, serious and cold, smart and capable; self-promoting and arrogant after a small promotion</td><td>honest, modest and courteous, helpful, generous, calm, and disciplined; serving people with morality,. not favoring power, not changing with their status, and treating others with a gentleman&#8217;s attitude</td><td>taking care of every single thing personally, lacking trust in others, lacking compassion, or greedy, harming others to benefit himself; weak in physical strength, or lazy</td><td>treating people humbly in appearance, but having a sinister heart; greedy in money; deceptive, even attaining his end by hook by crook</td></tr><tr><td>Body shape</td><td>red complexion, thin cheeks, small head, well proportioned shoulders, back and abdomen, full muscles, small hands and feet</td><td>white complexion, small head and square face, small hands, feet, shoulders, back and abdomen, light and thin body, strong heel</td><td>yellow complexion, big head. and round face, well- featured, full and strong shoulders and back, slightly large abdomen, slightly small hands and feet, plump and symmetrical whole body</td><td>slightly green skin, small head and long face, wide and thick shoulders and back, straight upper body, small hands and feet</td><td>black skin, wrinkled and not flat face, large head, like monkey cheek, narrow shoulders, large abdomen, long spine and back</td></tr><tr><td>Posture</td><td>the: whole-body swaying. when walking, fast pace of walking, sometimes convex chest and belly, with an arrogant attitude</td><td>the body swinging when walking, brisk and agile when standing, the head raising high and the hands being back contentedly</td><td>stable when walk, dignified and generous, peaceful and measured when behaving</td><td>self-contained in appearance, not generous in behavior not stable enough when standing, or the hands and feet being restless, walking like a sickle, difficult to straighten, or as if trying to hurt other people secretly</td><td>drooping eyes, seemingly humble; large body, but often with a cringing attitude; when walking, the body swinging, and the hands and feet moving</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2">Clinical Characteristics</td><td>Susceptible diseases</td><td>Adapted to spring and summer, not suitable for cold season as autumn and winter; autumn and winter are susceptible to external evil and being sick</td><td>Adapted to autumn and winter, not suitable for warm and hot season as spring and summer; spring and summer are susceptible to evil and being sick</td><td>Adapted to autumn and winter, not suitable for spring and summer; spring and summer are susceptible to external evil and being sick</td><td>Adapted to spring and summer, not suitable for cold season as autumn and winter; autumn and winter are susceptible to evil and being sick</td><td>Adapted to autumn and winter, not suitable for warm and hot season as spring and summer, spring and summer are. susceptible to. external evil and being sick</td></tr><tr><td>Key points of pattern and treatment</td><td>For people with exuberance of Yang with decline of Yin, the treatment should be adjustment of Yin and Yang. Yin could not be wearied on and Yang. could only be drained slightly. Major drainage and desertion of Yang Qi are prone to mania. Desertion of both Yin and Yang is prone to sudden death or unconsciousness.</td><td>For people with exuberance. Of Yang, with lesser Yin, small channel and big network,&nbsp; as well as Yin blood inside and Yang Qi outside are their basic pathogenesis characteristics The treatment should be repletion of Yin channel and drainage of Yang network. Excessive drainage of Yang Qi is prone to insufficiency of center Qi or various patterns of Qi desertion.</td><td>For people with balanced yin and Yang and smooth blood and vessel, superabundance or insufficiency of Yin, Yang, Qi and blood should be carefully diagnosed. Drain the superabundance while supplement the insufficiency Treat the same channel if without superabundance and insufficiency.</td><td>People: with exuberance of Yin with lesser Yang and small stomach and large intestines are susceptible to disharmony of six bowels, leading to small yang brightnesses wile large hand greater Yang vessels. Their scant Yyang Qi failing to contain blood is prone to Yin blood desertion and debilitated Yang Qi. When treating, diagnose dearly and adjust Qi and blood carefully.</td><td>For people with exuberance of Yin with decline of Yang, exuberance of Yin causes. thick and turbid blood while decline of Qi causes stoppage of defense Qi. Yin and&#8217; Yang are imbalanced. Their skins are thick. Their sinews and vessels are flaccid The treatment should be quick drainage f Yin turbidity and removal of disease Qi.&#8221;</td></tr><tr><td colspan="7">Note: This table is organized according to two chapters of Spiritual Pivot: twenty-five Types of People Divided According to Yin and Yang and Correspondence between Man and Nature.</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<figure data-wp-context="{&quot;imageId&quot;:&quot;6735b9741f082&quot;}" data-wp-interactive="core/image" class="wp-block-image size-thumbnail wp-lightbox-container"><img decoding="async" width="150" height="150" data-wp-class--hide="state.isContentHidden" data-wp-class--show="state.isContentVisible" data-wp-init="callbacks.setButtonStyles" data-wp-on-async--click="actions.showLightbox" data-wp-on-async--load="callbacks.setButtonStyles" data-wp-on-async-window--resize="callbacks.setButtonStyles" src="https://chinesezodiac.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/table-2-1-1-150x150.png" alt="" class="wp-image-118"/><button
			class="lightbox-trigger"
			type="button"
			aria-haspopup="dialog"
			aria-label="Enlarge image"
			data-wp-init="callbacks.initTriggerButton"
			data-wp-on-async--click="actions.showLightbox"
			data-wp-style--right="state.imageButtonRight"
			data-wp-style--top="state.imageButtonTop"
		>
			<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="12" height="12" fill="none" viewBox="0 0 12 12">
				<path fill="#fff" d="M2 0a2 2 0 0 0-2 2v2h1.5V2a.5.5 0 0 1 .5-.5h2V0H2Zm2 10.5H2a.5.5 0 0 1-.5-.5V8H0v2a2 2 0 0 0 2 2h2v-1.5ZM8 12v-1.5h2a.5.5 0 0 0 .5-.5V8H12v2a2 2 0 0 1-2 2H8Zm2-12a2 2 0 0 1 2 2v2h-1.5V2a.5.5 0 0 0-.5-.5H8V0h2Z" />
			</svg>
		</button></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clinical Application</h2>



<p>Broadly speaking, in the process of diagnosis and treatment of diseases, clinicians consciously or unconsciously use the speech-guided therapy to guide and unblock the psychological and emotional disorders of patients, so as to relieve their doubts and worries, dispel emotional factors that cause diseases, as well as to help patients treat diseases correctly and develop reasonable living habits. Therefore, as the most widely used psychological treatment method in clinical practice, it is of great significance for the treatment of various diseases. As far as the characteristics of this therapy are concerned, it has an irreplaceable therapeutic effect on psychogenic and emotional disorders associated with psychogenicity, situational diseases and other diseases.</p>



<p>For some patients due to doubts, they should be diagnosed and treated according to their pathogenic causes in order to recover without medical help. For example, mistaking the shadow of a bow in one&#8217;s cup as a snake, a case described in The Book of Jin: Biography of Yue Guang is one of the examples of the ancients applying this therapy. He Jie is invited by Yue Guang to have food and drink. After a few cups of wine, he suddenly sees a small snake at the bottom of the cup and feels a foreign body in the throat. Thereafter, doubts of the small snake eating his viscera cause worse and worse heartache. It is not effective to invite doctors or take medicines. Later, Yue Guang asks the cause and is told what has happened. Yue Guang looks around again and sees a snake-like bow hanging on the wall, which means the snake in the cup is the shadow of the bow. Yue sets the cup on the original place and asks He Jie if there is a snake in the cup? He Jie answers yes. Yue Guang &#8220;tells him why before He Jie suddenly understands it and his severe illness recovers immediately&#8221;. The heartache of the case is caused by the doubt of a small snake in the cup. The doctor and the medicine are ineffective. Finally, the facts are told to enlighten. The doubts are dispelled and the disease is cured. The case not only expounds the intrinsic link between the cause and development of the disease, but also shows that &#8220;heart disease is in need of heart medicine&#8221; is one of the main methods of clinical application of this therapy.</p>



<p>The edificatory speech therapy is of great significance in the treatment of physical and emotional diseases due to many comprehensive factors. Miao Zhongchun,a famous doctor in Ming Dynasty, treats Gu Zhonggong whose numb and cold left foot develops to the numbness of the whole body and unconsciousness that is so worrisome. When treating, Miao first analyses that the disease is caused by noninteraction of heart and kidney and dissipation of heart blood due to mind loss, heart damage and sexual taxation. Then he says &#8220;noninteraction of heart and kidney will cause separation of Yin and Yang which will be serious&#8221; to alert him. Then he urges to &#8220;clear mind and dispel lust&#8221; and warns the patient to persist in &#8220;securing of true essence, containment of Yin and Yang, and physical and emotional comfort&#8221;. Finally, the patient is prescribed with medicine and guided the way of health maintenance. In Miao&#8217;s case, he treats mainly with explaining, counselling and other edificatory speech methods, combined with drug therapy as well as physical and mental adjustment methods. It manifests a principle of &#8220;treating the disease must first treat spirit&#8221;.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Attentions</h2>



<p>During the diagnosis and treatment, the therapy should comprehensively examine and analyze the patient&#8217;s temperament type, affective disorder and pathogenesis. The cause of the disease, age, gender, cultural literacy, economic status, living environment, social status, etc. should be considered to formulate a corresponding edificatory speech therapy. These are the key to obtain a good psychotherapy effect in clinical application.</p>



<p>As the main medium of interpersonal communication, language can either play positive therapeutic effects to relieve the patient&#8217;s fear, tension, sorrow, doubts and other negative emotions and emotional disorders and to strengthen his conviction to defeat disease during the treatment process, or the opposite effect of mental burden aggravation or disease worsening due to inappropriate speeches of the doctor or relatives. Therefore, in the application of this therapy, the speaking skills and methods should be paid attention to conduct guidance from person to person. Doctors should do their best to &#8220;unbind and open the glue&#8221; such as enlightening with reason, emotionally moving, or alerting the wrong, or stretching the mind when using this therapy. &#8220;For those who prefer luck, endanger; for those with numerous worries, comfort; for those not convinced, counsel is difficult; for those skeptical, deep words are envious.&#8221;(Required Readings from Medical Ancestors) Doctors should pay attention to these similar experiences.</p>



<p>For some patients who have hidden feelings, the doctor should pay attention to the way of asking and the surrounding environment during the conversation to &#8220;close the door and shut the windows, tie yourself to the patient, repeatedly inquire about his feelings, adapt your treatment to his sentiments&#8221;(lain Questions: Discourse on Moving the Essence and Changing the Qi).The doctor should also explain to the patient that the doctor&#8217;s responsibility for the confidentiality of the patient&#8217;s condition in order to obtain the patient&#8217;s trust and cooperation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Comments</h2>



<p>The use of Edificatory Speech therapy in TCM has a long history. As early as Qin and Han Dynasties, a relatively systematic theory has been formed and applied to clinical treatment. It is not only more detailed and reasonable in terms of observation and classification than temperament classification theory of Hippocrates, the father of Western medicine, of the same time, but also more suitable for clinical treatment. Many methods open a new prospect in modern psychology. Modern medicine noticed the impact of social- psychological factors on health and disease only in the mid-20th century, especially after the 1970s, and gradually carried out psychological counseling and psychotherapy. Therefore, the comprehensive organization and in-depth exploration of theory and treatment methods of TCM psychology will not only help the development and improvement of TCM itself, but also play a beneficial role in promoting the development of modern medicine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introduction to the Emotional Therapy of Traditional Chinese Medicine</title>
		<link>/p/introduction-emotional-therapy.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 14:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Traditional Chinese Medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotional Therapy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Emotional theory is an important part of Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) and TCM's holistic view. It emphasizes that people's emotional activities (including mental, consciousness, and thinking activities) are based on the function of bowels and viscera. Emotional activities are of significant individual differences and influenced by the natural and social environment.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Emotional therapy is an important part of Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) and TCM&#8217;s holistic view. It emphasizes that people&#8217;s emotional activities (including mental, consciousness, and thinking activities) are based on the function of bowels and viscera. Emotional activities are of significant individual differences and influenced by the natural and social environment.</p>



<p>Emotional activities mentioned in ancient books include joy, anger, sadness, happiness, love, dislike, desire, worry, thought, sorrow, fear, surprise, doubt, hate, etc. There was a variety of emotional classification methods in ancient times, such as:</p>



<p>The Commentary of Zuo puts forward the &#8220;Six Minds&#8221;, which says, &#8220;People&#8217;s like, dislike, joy, anger, sorrow and happiness are born of six Qi. Therefore, etiquette is set to restrain six minds&#8221; in the Year 25 of Duke Zhao in the Commentary of Zuo. Xuncius called &#8220;Six Minds&#8221; as &#8220;Six Affects&#8221;. Year 25 of Duke Zhao in the Commentary of Zuo records: &#8221; Like, dislike, joy, anger, sorrow and happiness of nature are called affects. &#8220;Rite and Luck of The Book of Rites has records of&#8221; seven affects&#8221;: &#8220;What are the human affects? They are joy, anger, sorrow, fear, love, dislike and desire.&#8221;</p>



<p>There are also many discussions about emotions in Internal Classic. For example, Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on Phenomena Corresponding to Yin and Yang records: &#8220;Man has the five viscera which transform the five Qi, thereby generating joy, angry, sadness, anxiety, and fear.&#8221; Plain Questions: Discourse on Pain says: &#8220;Hundreds of diseases arise out of Qi. The Qi rises while one is angry. And it relaxes while he is joyous. When one is sad, then the Qi dissipates. When one is in fear, then the Qi moves down. When one is frightened, then the Qi is in disorder. &#8220;In the former discourse, joy, anger, sorrow, anxiety, and fear are called &#8220;five minds&#8221;, while in the latter discourse anger, joy, sorrow, fear, anxiety, and fright are the six kinds.</p>



<p>Chen Wuze of Song Dynasty proposes in Treatise on Disease, Patterns, and Prescriptions Related to Unification of the Three Etiologies: &#8220;Seven affects are joy, anger, anxiety, thought, sorrow, fear and fright. &#8220;This statement is more reasonable than the &#8220;seven affects&#8221; in The Book of Rites.</p>



<p>Among the above classifications, the most influential to TCM are the &#8220;five minds&#8221; of Huangdi&#8217;s Internal Classic and the &#8220;seven affects&#8221; of Treatise on Disease, Patterns, and Prescriptions Related to Unification of the Three Etiologies. The two are often called&#8221; affect-mind&#8221;.</p>



<p>Modern psychology believes that there are four basic types of emotions, namely happiness, sadness, anger and fear, and other emotions derive from the four. For the &#8220;five minds&#8221; of Internal Classic, joy, anger, anxiety and fear, which belong to the emotional process, just match the four types of emotions, if thought-a process of cognition in terms of modern psychology, removed.</p>



<p>Since the Qin and Han Dynasties, ancient scholars have carried out many discussions on the generating principles of emotions, and they believe that emotions are sense of things and are stimulated by the external stimuli. For example, Huai Nan Tzu: Original Tao says: &#8220;Wisdom of things generates likes and dislikes.&#8221; Zhu Xi also says: &#8220;Joy, anger, grief and happiness originate from sense of things, which likes the shape in the mirror. Is there a shadow if there&#8217;s nothing in front of the mirror?&#8221; Li Zhongzi, a doctor in Ming Dynasty, attributes the factors that stimulate emotional response to two categories, namely &#8220;encounter&#8221; and &#8220;need&#8221;. The former involves external stimuli and the latter relates to one&#8217;s own desires. Affect and desire no doubt belong to &#8220;human nature&#8221;, however, excessive activities will cause damage to the body and mind. Therefore, passionate activities should be moderate, neither too many nor too few. Just as emphasized in Fine Prescriptions in Emergency, &#8220;anxiety, thought, joy and anger are ones without which man cannot live while excessive of which will damage the five viscera.&#8221;</p>



<p>The method of regulation and treatment based on emotion theory is called Emotional Therapy. Emotional Therapy generally does not involve drugs, acupuncture, surgery and other &#8220;tangible&#8221; treatments. It affects the patient&#8217;s psychological activities, arouses the positive factors of patients&#8217; prevention and treatment of diseases, and promotes or adjusts the functional activities of the body to achieve a therapeutic or healing effect by means of speech, behavior and specially arranged scenes. It is similar to psychotherapy in modern medicine in terms of methods, means and clinical effects.</p>



<p>There is no such thing as psychology or psychotherapy in TCM. However, there are many similar titles in the traditional literature. The most influential ones are &#8220;treating spirit&#8221; from Plain Questions: Discourse on Treasuring Life and Preserving Physical Appearance, &#8220;treating reflection &#8220;from Supplement to Classified Case Records of Famous Physicians,&#8221; curing heart &#8220;from Secret Record in a Green-blue Pouch, &#8220;restraining of human affairs&#8221; from Danxi&#8217;s Experiential Therapy and so on. TCM contains a wealth of theory and practical experience of Emotional Therapy.&#8221; Heart disease still needs heart medicine&#8221; is a famous saying that everyone knows. Emotional Therapy is actually one of the earliest forms of treatment. It used to be the dominant form of treatment in ancient times.</p>



<p>American scholar Murphy once said: &#8220;The first hometown of the world psychology is in China.&#8221; Prescriptions for Fifty-two Diseases, compiled from the Mawangdui Han Tombs, an ancient medical book researched to be earlier than Internal Classic, boasts 35 cases of &#8220;invoking origin to treat diseases&#8221;.</p>



<p>Internal Classic, published more than 2 000 years ago, is not only the origin of TCM theory, but also the earliest work of emotional illness and its treatment. It recognizes that human psychological factors are closely related to the occurrence, development and prognosis of diseases. In terms of treatment, it places &#8220;treating spirit&#8221; at the head of various methods. Treatments such as &#8220;needles, (pointed) stones, and toxic drugs&#8221; must stimulate the patient&#8217;s spirit to have the therapeutic effect. Spiritual Pivot: Instructions of the Teacher says: &#8220;It is human who dislike death and prefer living. The doctor should tell the patients what are harmful to their health, let them know what are good for their health, guides them to do what they like for restoring their health and tries to straighten them out of their anxiety. If the doctor has done all that is required, even a most unreasonable person will follow his advice. &#8220;The penetrating comment is still widely used as a classic emotional (psycho) treatment theory. Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on the Progression of the Five Periods and Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on Phenomena Corresponding to Yin and Yang have recognized the dialectical relationship physiologically and pathologically between mental factors and viscera, as well as emotions and emotions, and created the therapy of mutual domination of emotions, that is, &#8220;Anger harms liver; sadness dominates anger. Joy harms heart; fear dominates joy. Thought harms spleen; anger dominates thought. Anxiety harms lung; joy dominates anxiety. Fear harms kidney; thought dominates fear.&#8221; cleverly based on the principle of &#8220;rescuing tendency with tendency&#8221;.</p>



<p>Plain Questions: Discourse on Moving the Essence and Changing the Qi says: &#8220;When the people in antiquity treated a disease, they simply moved the essence and changed the Qi. They were able to invoke the origin and any disease came to an end.&#8221; Spiritual Pivot: Thief-like Wind further elaborates the theory of invoking origin to treat diseases.</p>



<p>Huangdi said,&#8221; Some people who are never attacked by evil Qi and have no emotional changes like fear and terror suddenly fall ill. What is the cause? Is it caused by ghost and evil?&#8221; Qibo said, &#8220;This is also due to latent evil that stays inside the body but has never attacked. When there appear such emotional changes like disliking something or desiring something, it will cause disorders of blood and Qi which will interact with the latent pathogenic factors inside the body. Such interior changes are subtle, invisible and noiseless. That is why it occurs like the haunting of ghosts and devils.&#8221; Huangdi said, &#8220;Why it can be cured by praying?&#8221; Qibo said, &#8220;Sorcerers in ancient times knew the causes and treatments of diseases. What they usually did was to find out the cause of a disease first and then treated it by prayers&#8221;.</p>



<p>According to this, Zhang Jiebin, a famous doctor of the Ming Dynasty, makes a further elucidation in Classified Classic: &#8220;Knowing its prevalence and origination can be cured by invoking. It is to seek the origin of the disease and release the ghost in heart&#8230; Once the root is obtained, there is a therapy. Therefore, invoking won&#8217;t be ineffective after examination of his dislike, plan, prevalence and origination.&#8221;</p>



<p>In addition, &#8220;hiccup also can be stopped by sudden shock&#8221; from Plain Questions: Discourse on Strange Diseases, while &#8220;fright is treated by calming&#8221; from Plain Questions: Comprehensive Discourse on the Essentials of the Most Reliable and other related records reveal that emotional related therapy has been applied in the clinical practice. As for &#8220;They exhaled and inhaled essence Qi, they stood for themselves and guarded their spirit. Muscles and flesh were like one.&#8221; from Plain Questions: Discourse on the True Qi Endowed by Heaven in High Antiquity, &#8220;guiding-pulling and pressing-lifting&#8221; from Plain Questions: Discourse on Different Therapeutic Patterns Suitable for Use in Different Cardinal Points, as well as &#8220;tranquilizing the mind and eliminating avarice, holding the breath (only inhalation and no exhalation) for seven times&#8221; from Plain Questions: Discussion on Acupuncture Methods and so on advocate positive Qigong or guidance methods to tranquil heart, guard spirit and regulate spirt to achieve the purpose of disease prevention and treatment. These statements in Internal Classic are not only the earliest psychiatric treatment in the world to treat Qi and blood disorder through invoking origin, that is, to pray and interpret the cause of the disease, or to be freed from the sufferings of spiritual concern, but also reflect the pivotal therapeutic status of invoking origin at that time. Therefore, from invoking origin appeared in Internal Classic to the specially setting up of departments of medicine, needle, massage and exorcism (invoking origin)in Tang Dynasty, the hard journey of emotional (psychological) treatment of TCM can be seen from germination to maturity.</p>



<p>Although there is no discussion about emotional treatment in Treatise on Cold Damage, Zhang Zhongjing clearly states in Synopsis of the Golden Chamber: On Pulse, Symptom Complex and Transmission of Diseases of the Viscera, Bowels, Channels and Collaterals that it should be paid attention to regulate the mind and body during the treatment of the disease.</p>



<p>There are a large number of masters to treat emotional illnesses during the Jin and Yuan Dynasties. For example, Zhang Zihe emphasizes in Confucians&#8217; Duties to Parents: Diseases Contracted From Nine Qi Be Treated One With Another: &#8220;Sorrow can treat anger, wih painful words to move; joy can treat sorrow, with jokes to amuse; fear can treat joy, with threatening words to intimidate; anger can treat thought, with insulting words to enrage; thought can treat fear, with worrying words to deprive.&#8221; &#8220;Idleness can treat taxation.&#8221;&#8221;Accustomization can treat fright.&#8221; &#8220;Diseases contracted from nine Qi can be treated one with another.&#8221; He extremely exquisitely interprets the theory of affect-mind mutual domination in Internal Classic. His emotional medical records are ingenious in design, in-depth and complete in treatment, and classic in appraisal. These medical records boast a very high-level no matter from the theoretical analysis of TCM or from the perspective of modern psychotherapy, and extend the considerable influence to psychology and its treatment not only mainland China but also the world. Luo Tianyi, Zhu Danxi, Jia Sicheng, etc. of the same period also leave many fruitful emotional medical cases. It should be noted that in the minority medicines of our country, there are applications of similar methods, such as Yelv Dilu&#8217;s enraging to discharge toxin in Liao Dynasty.</p>



<p>Miao Zhongchun in the Ming Dynasty says in Dissemination of the Classic of Materia Medica: On Seven Affects: &#8220;Affects are mental, uncertain, and untraceable. They appear in the encounter with circumstances and their stagnations are difficult to free. &#8220;And there is the possibility of &#8220;recurrence in the future&#8221;. For the treatment, &#8220;It is only suitable to condemn insight with insight and to condemn reason with reason, which means heart disease will be treated with heart medicine. If so, stagnation is freed; binding is transformed; affects separate with circumstances without interference. The place is still, and the heart is calm.How can be burdened with seven affects?&#8221; Zhang Jingyue makes new progress based on the interpretation of Emotional Therapy in Internal Classic. Classified Classic: On treatments has made a profound analysis of ghost spirit and invoking origin with the citation of emotional treatment records of his and others. Jing Yue&#8217;s Collected Works makes a historic contribution to the treatment of malingering. The Ming Dynasty witnesses the most emotional treatment records in the history of TCM.</p>



<p>Wu Shangxian of Qing Dynasty says in Rhymed Discourse for External Remedies: &#8220;Contraction of lust cannot be cured with medicinals. A disease of seven affects should be treated with affects.&#8221; There are only a few scattered records about psychotherapy during this period, and most of them are paired with or subordinated to acupuncture or medicine. However, it has a positive significance in terms of the collection of psychotherapy medical records. Chen Menglei has more than 30 cases of psychotherapy in Complete Medical Works of the Library Collection, Ancient and Modern.Wei Zhixiu&#8217;s Supplement to Classified Case Records of Famous Physicians also has more than 20 cases that are divided into categories by malingering, love-sickness and so on. Yu Zhen&#8217;s Comments on Ancient and Modern Cases Records is good at the selection of cases and incisive in the comments although its case number is fewer than the previous two books.</p>



<p>From the rich clinical practice, doctors of the past generations sum up that &#8220;a heart disease still needs heart medicine&#8221;, and propose that &#8220;to treat heart disease without knowing the medicine and its properties, dosage and producing area but with a good effect&#8221;. It can be seen that &#8220;heart medicine&#8221; is not a real drug but an emotional adjustment. Zhao Yanhui of Qing Dynasty clearly states in Medical Discussion Notes of Cun Cun-zhai that &#8220;ruthless herbs and trees cannot treat affect diseases and the refractory people or diseases should be treated with a silver tongue&#8221;. For those doctors who do not pay attention to emotional treatment, Treasured Mirror of Oriental Medicine has given sharp criticism:&#8221;Ancient sacred doctor can treat people&#8217;s heart to prevent from becoming sick; today&#8217;s doctors only treat people&#8217;s diseases without knowing the heart, which likes attending to trifles and neglecting essentials. Isn’t it stupid to desire a healing by attacking the course without knowing the source?&#8221;</p>



<p>As an important part of TCM, Emotional Therapy has contributed a lot to the maintenance of Chinese people&#8217;s health. Psychological disorders, psychosomatic diseases, neuropsychiatric diseases and social maladjustment have become the main factors affecting the health of modern people. Their harmfulness is rapidly rising, attracting the attention of the whole society, and requiring a lot of energy and material resources to study and tackle. For these psychotic and psychosomatic diseases, the simple use of medicine is often insufficient or even ineffective, while the psychological treatment plays a positive role.</p>



<p>At present, psychotherapy in China basically introduces and imitates Western theories and models, and is deeply influenced by Western culture and social customs. The credibility and feasibility of these results have certain geographical restrictions in spite of the rigorous design, advanced means and empirical evidence. There are many differences between China and the West in historical evolution, cultural traditions, social structure, economic conditions, values, customs and other social and cultural aspects. The personality characteristics and psychological state of Chinese people are also very different from those of Westerners, resulting in unique psychological problems and disorders. Even for the same type of psychological problems and disorders, Chinese and Western people often differ in their specific causes and symptoms. China’s psychological treatment cannot simply and mechanically apply Western theories and models, and must have an in-depth understanding of Chinese traditional culture. Emotional Therapy is basically consistent with the definition, means and effects of modern psychotherapy. Chinese psychotherapy with traditional Chinese cultural characteristics is more suitable for personality characteristics of Chinese.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brief History of the Development of Acupuncture and Moxibustion</title>
		<link>/p/brief-history-acupuncture-moxibustion.html</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KBL]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 08:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Acupuncture and Moxibustion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://chinesezodiac.org/?p=104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Acupuncture and moxibustion has a long history from its birth to maturity. Legends about the origin of acupuncture therapy can be traced back to the period of clan commune in the primitive society of China. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Acupuncture and moxibustion has a long history from its birth to maturity.</p>



<p>Legends about the origin of acupuncture therapy can be traced back to the period of clan commune in the primitive society of China. For example, there were records in ancient books about Fu Xi &#8220;tasting hundreds of herbs and making nine kind of needles&#8221; and “acupuncture therapy originated after Huang Di consulting Qi Bo,Bo Gao,ShaoYu”. The actual originating time of acupuncture therapy should have been a long period after the application of &#8220;Bian stone&#8221; in the Neolithic Age, although Fu Xi, etc. were representatives in ancient legends.</p>



<p>“Bian stone”, the prototype or predecessor of needles, is the product of ancient people&#8217;s experience accumulation in their life and labor. It has gone through a long time from unexpected findings that the stone&#8217;s pressing or puncturing the body surface can cure disease to the purposeful processing of the stone into Bian stone for exclusive treatment use. When humans entered the Neolithic Age, refined stone needles appeared; after that, the emergence of various kinds of needles, such as bone needles, ceramic needles, bamboo needles, etc., especially metal needles after the invention of metallurgy by human, greatly promoted the development of acupuncture method.</p>



<p>The origin of moxibustion therapy can be traced back to the primitive society after humans learned to use fire. During the process of using fire, people gradually realized the therapeutic effect of warmth and heat. Then moxibustion therapy was formed through the long-term practice.</p>



<p>After the creation of acupuncture and moxibustion therapies, the theoretical system of acupuncture and moxibustion, with the accumulation of practical experience and the penetration of ancient philosophy and other natural sciences, began to form, develop, and be improved constantly, which can be roughly summarized in the following periods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Theoretical Beginning Period</h2>



<p>This period mainly is a preliminary understanding of acupuncture and moxibustion through personal clinical practice, about before the appearance of Huangdi’s Internal Classic. Representatives include the legendary figures Qi Bo, Bo Gao, Shao Yu, and the famous doctors Yi Huan and Yi He in the Spring and Autumn period. In 1973,there were two ancient meridian documents in the silk medical manuscripts unearthed from the Han Tomb No.3 of Mawangdui, Changsha, Hunan province, namely, Moxibustion Classic for Eleven Hand- Foot Meridians and Moxibustion Classic for Eleven Yin-Yang Meridians. The course and distribution of the meridians, symptoms and moxibustion methods are discussed in the books. These are the earliest extant literature on acupuncture and moxibustion, reflecting the early appearance of the theoretical understanding of the meridian system.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Theoretical Establishment Period</h2>



<p>This period is from Warring States to Qin and Han Dynasties, which is marked by the completion of Huangdi’s Internal Classic.</p>



<p>Huangdi’s Internal Classic, which establishes a basic theoretical system for traditional Chinese medicine, expounds the physiology and pathology of the human body, the methods and principles of diagnosis and treatment, with the main content of Yin and Yang, five elements, viscera, meridian, Qi, blood and body fluid. The book also discusses in detail the</p>



<p>course of meridians, symptoms, acupoints, and methods, indications and contraindications of acupuncture and moxibustion, etc. Particularly, there are a lot of space dedicated to the theory and clinical treatment of acupuncture and moxibustion in Spiritual Pival, therefore, it is called “Acupuncture Classic&#8221;, which marks the basic formation of the theoretical system of acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<p>The records of the acupuncture appliances, “Nine Needles”, are first seen in Huangdi Internal Classic in the current extant literatures. The invention of the Nine Needles is not only the ultimate development of ancient Chinese acupuncture and moxibustion appliances but also the wisdom crystallization of ancient Chinese physicians&#8217; continuous innovation, providing a powerful “weapon&#8221; for acupuncture and moxibustion clinical treatment of various diseases. Even to this day, the development and clinical application of acupuncture tools are still difficult to exceed the scope of the ancient Nine Needles.</p>



<p>The Nine Needles refer to Chanzhen (sagittate needle),Yuanzhen(round-pointed needle),Dizhen (arrow-shaped needle),Fengzhen(sharp needle),Pizhen(sword-shaped needle),Yuanlizhen(round-sharp needle),Haozhen(filiform needle),Changzhen(long needle),and Dazhen(large needle).They have different shape,length,size,and application. Under the social background and economic development level at that time, the shape, specification and indications of these Nine Needles were strictly stipulated, which showed the continuous improvement of acupuncture tools during the practice of acupuncture and moxibustion therapy in disease treatment, and eventually developed to an unprecedentedly high level.</p>



<p>.There are many records about and praising comments on the Nine Needles in Huangdi’s Internal Classic For examples, the Section Discussion on the Nine Needles in the book Spiritual pivot records that &#8220;The Nine Needles were developed according to the law of the heaven and the earth. The great number of the heaven and the earth begins with one and ends with nine&#8221; The Section Application of Needles in the book Spiritual Pivot states that &#8220;The key of needling lies in the reasonable application of the needles. The Nine Needles have different usages. They are either long, or short, or large, or small. They are used for different purposes. Wrong use of them cannot cure diseases. “The Section Diagnosing the Interior by Examining the Exterior in the book Spiritual pivot states that &#8220;the theory of the Nine Needles is so abstruse that it cannot accommodate anything when it becomes small and nothing can accommodate it when it grows large. It is something that is so deep that nothing can exist below it and so high that nothing can cover it. It is so subtle and abstruse that it permeates through everywhere without any limitation. “The Section Explanation of Acupuncture in the book Plains Questions documents that “the Nine Needles correspond to the earth and heaven, the four seasons and Yin and Yang. I&#8217;d like to know the reason and pass it on to the later generations as the essential methods. “The reason why the Nine Needles are so highly praised not only is that their treatment range greatly exceeds that of Bian stone, but also each needle has its own unique treatment characteristics.</p>



<p>Classic of Difficulties was written in Han Dynasty or so, with the main purpose of illuminating Huangdi’s Internal Classic, Its expounding of eight extra meridians and source Qi supplements the content of Huangdi&#8217;s Internal Classic, Simultaneously, it also proposes the eight meeting acupoints and uses five elements theory to explain the theory and application of the five transport acupoints in detail. The lost Treatment Essentials of acupuncture and</p>



<p>Moxibustion Points should have been a monograph on acupoints during this period. Hua Tuo also had great attainments in acupuncture and moxibustion, and founded “Huatuo Jiaji acupoints”. Zhang Zhongjing of the Eastern Han Dynasty founded the six-meridian pattern differentiation and also recorded many acupuncture and moxibustion prescriptions in Treatise on Cold Damage, advocating syndrome differentiation and the combined use of acupuncture and medicine. These academic achievements have become the cornerstone for the development of acupuncture and moxibustion in later generations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rapid Academic Development Period</h2>



<p>During the Ganlu period (256-260)of Wei and Jin Dynasties, Huangfu Mi compiled the relevant contents from Plains Questions, Spiritual Pivot and Treatment Essentials of Acupuncture and Moxibustion Points into the book A-B Classic of Acupuncture and Moxibustion. It collected the name, location and acupuncture and moxibustion techniques of 348 acupoints and systematically categorized the acupuncture and moxibustion treatment of various diseases. It was the earliest extant monograph on acupuncture and moxibustion, which was another summary of acupuncture and moxibustion after Huangdi&#8217;s Internal Classic, and served as a link between past and future in the development history of acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<p>With the clinical deepening of acupuncture and moxibustion in the Western and Eastern Jin Dynasties and the Northern and Southern Dynasties, many doctors and monographs on acupuncture and moxibustion appeared. For example, Ge Hong,a famous doctor in the Jin Dynasty, compiled the book Handbook of Prescriptions for emergency, containing 109 acupuncture and moxibustion prescriptions, 99 of which were moxibustion prescriptions. This significantly promoted the clinical application of moxibustion therapy.</p>



<p>Acupuncture and moxibustion greatly developed in the Sui and Tang Dynasties. It became a specialized discipline in the early Tang Dynasty, and the imperial court also provided professional titles such as &#8220;acupuncturist&#8221; and &#8220;moxibuster&#8221;.In the Sui and Tang Dynasties, Zhen Quan and Sun Simiao were all major medical experts proficient in various fields of traditional Chinese medicine and also made outstanding achievements in acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<p>Zhen Quan authored Acupuncture Principles, Copies of acupuncture Classic and Human Bodys Meridia Illustration (all lost). During the Zhenguan period (627-649)of Tang Dynasty, the government organized Zhen Quan and others to revise Illustrated Manual of Human Body’s Meridian, which showed the importance attached to acupuncture and moxibustion at that time. Sun Simiao extensively collected the acupuncture and moxibustion experience of the doctors of the previous generations in Important Prescriptions Iorth a Thousand Gold for Emergency and drew Three-Angle Lustration of Human Body’s Meridian, in which the twelve meridians of human body&#8217;s front side and back were marked with five colors, and the eight extra meridians with green colors, which become the earliest colored meridian acupoint illustration in history (already lost).Moreover, he also created “Ashi acupoint&#8221; and “finger Cun method”. Moreover, Wang Tao&#8217;s Arcane Essentials from the Imperial Library and Cui Zhiti&#8217;s Moxibustion Prescription for Bone-Steaming Ferer contained great number of moxibustion treatment experience. It can be seen that in the Jin and Tang Dynasties moxibustion was widely used.</p>



<p>The national acupuncture and moxibustion education system started from the Tang Dynasty. Its Imperial Medical Academy was responsible for medical education and offered acupuncture and moxibustion major, with “one doctor, one assistant, ten acupuncturists, twenty staffs, and twenty students&#8221;, which laid the foundation for the standardized education of acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<p>During Song,Jin and Yuan Dynasties after Tang Dynasty, China established more advanced acupuncture and moxibustion institution and education system, with acupuncture department and moxibustion department offered. And Plains Questions, Classic of Difficulties and A-B Classic of Acupuncture and Moxibustion were stipulated as compulsory subjects in teaching.</p>



<p>Wang Weiyi, the famous expert of acupuncture and moxibustion of Northern Song Dynasty, pioneered the acupoint textual research and correction as well as the invention of teaching tools for acupuncture and moxibustion. At that time, acupuncture and moxibustion treatment was very popular. However, there were often undesirable medical errors or accidents caused by such factors as the difficulty in copying and engraving ancient acupuncture and moxibustion books, the missing of inscribed bamboo slips, or even mistakes. Therefore, Wang Weiyi and other experts suggested several times that it is urgent to compile a standardized acupuncture map and cast a bronze acupuncture figure model marked with the twelve meridian routes and acupoints to standardize the theory of the meridians and acupoints.</p>



<p>Wang Weiyi conducted textual research and correction again for 354 acupoints. In the fourth year of Tansheng period (1026),he authored Illustrated Manual of Acupoints of the Bonge Fignre and engraved it and inscribed it on monuments that were promulgated by the government. He personally designed the bronze acupuncture figure model from the embryo molding, model making to the whole process of casting, worked with the craftsmen to overcome the technical difficulties, and finally cast two acupuncture figure models in 1027 for teaching and examination purposes, which were called &#8220;sacred bronze figures “by later generations(Figure 1-1).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image alignright size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="329" height="902" src="https://chinesezodiac.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Figure-1-1-Newly-cast-bronze-acupuncture-figure-model.png" alt="Figure 1-1 Newly-cast bronze acupuncture figure model of the Northern Song Dynasty" class="wp-image-107" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Figure-1-1-Newly-cast-bronze-acupuncture-figure-model.png 329w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Figure-1-1-Newly-cast-bronze-acupuncture-figure-model-109x300.png 109w" sizes="(max-width: 329px) 100vw, 329px" /></figure>



<p>The “sacred bronze figures&#8221; had three basic characteristics: one is the “front-back separability”, that is, it can be separated into the front and back pieces, on which the meridian course and acupuncture holes were engraved; the second is completeness, with five Zang-organs and six Fu-organs that can be seen after separation; and the third is empty interior, with yellow wax on the exterior, which can be filled with water (mercury) and clothed. When the medical practitioner is tested, the criterion for judging whether the acupoints are selected accurately is the immediate flow out of the water (mercury) as soon as the needle is inserted into the sacred bronze figures, Illustrated Mannal of Acupoints of the Bonse Figure and the bronze acupuncture figure model became the world&#8217;s first government-promulgated national standards for meridian and acupoint literature and teaching model, which effectively promoted the development of acupuncture and moxibustion in the direction of normalization and standardization.</p>



<p>The invention of printing technique in Song Dynasty greatly promoted the accumulation and dissemination of acupuncture and moxibustion literature, and the acupuncture and moxibustion monographs increased significantly. For example,Moxibustion Tecbnique for Emergency by Wenren Qinian,the acupuncture expert of the Southern Song Dynasty, and Classic of Nourishing Life of Acupuncture and Moxibustion by Wang Zhizhong all were practical monographs that summarized the acupuncture and moxibustion clinical experiences. Wang collected many folk clinical experiences in his book. He was good at moxibustion and using tenderness point to diagnose and treat diseases.</p>



<p>He Ruoyu in Jin Dynasty created &#8220;the midnight-noon ebb-flow acupuncture method&#8221; and advocated the time-oriented acupoint selecting method, which had a greater impact on later generations. MA Danyang and Dou Hanqing both had certain attainments in acupoint clinical application, with Ma good at &#8220;heavenly star twelve acupoints&#8221; and Dou good at “the confluence acupoints of eight extraordinary meridians”.</p>



<p>In Yuan Dynasty, Hua Bairen conducted textual research and correction for the meridian course and its related acupoints, and authored Elucidation of Fourteen Channels, in which the Governor vessel, the Conception vessel, and the twelve meridians were collectively called the &#8220;fourteen meridians&#8221; and provided valuable literature for the study of meridians in later generations. In addition, China&#8217;s ethnic minorities also made contributions to acupuncture and moxibustion. For example, Huai Bilie,a Mongolian bachelor of Imperial Hanlin Academy, once wrote Valuable Sketch of Acupoint Selection Along the Meridians. Although it was lost, its original appearance can be deduced from the book Elucidation of Fourteen Channels.</p>



<p>The Ming Dynasty was a relatively active period in the development history of acupuncture and moxibustion. The specific manifestations included the collation and research of acupuncture and moxibustion literatures of the previous generations, the emergence of many academic schools and controversies, the creation of abundant acupuncture manipulations, the collective summarization of &#8220;extraordinary acupoints&#8221; for the acupoints irrelevant to the meridians,etc.And the representative doctors and works included Chen Hui&#8217;s Miraculous Effective Classic of Acupuncture, Xu Feng&#8217;s Great Complete Collection of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Gao Wu&#8217;s A Collection of Gems in Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Yang Jizhou&#8217;s Great Compendium of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Wu Kun&#8217;s Acupuncture Principles in Six Lolumes,Wang Ji&#8217;s Catechism of Acupuncture and Moxibustion, Zhang Jiebin&#8217;s Pictorial Appendices to The Classified Classic, Li Shizhen&#8217;s Consideration of the Eight extra meridians and so on.</p>



<p>Great Complete Collection of Acupuncture and Moxibustion collects and comments acupuncture manipulations. Catechism of Acupuncture and Moxibustion is a book of academic contention with more than 80 questions and answers on acupuncture and moxibustion academic questions. Great Compendium of Acupuncture and Moxibustion is regarded as the third major summary of acupuncture and moxibustion after A-B Classic of Acupuncture and Moxibustion. Based on Yang Jizhou&#8217;s patrimonial book Mystery and Essentials of Acupuncture, it compiles the academic views and practical experiences of acupuncture and moxibustion in various generations, and is an important reference for studying acupuncture and moxibustion in later generations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Academic Recession Period</h2>



<p>Acupuncture and moxibustion in Qing Dynasty began to decline, when the doctors paid priority to Chinese herbal medicine and neglected acupuncture, especially the rulers of the Qing Dynasty abolished the department of acupuncture and moxibustion in the Imperial Hospital in 1822 for the ridiculous reason that &#8220;acupuncture and moxibustion is not suitable for the emperor”. Generally speaking, the works of acupuncture and moxibustion in this period were less innovative. The main representatives included Wu Qian&#8217;s acupuncture Essential Teachings of Golden Mirror of the Medical ncestors,Liao Runhong&#8217;s Complete Works on Acupuncture and Li Xuechuan&#8217;s Compilation of Acupuncture and Moxibustion.</p>



<p>After the defeat of the Opium War, Western learning gradually spreaded eastward, and missionary hospitals and Western medicine universities were established in various places, with discrimination and exclusion to traditional Chinese medicine. During the period of the Republic of China, there were proposals to abolish traditional Chinese medicine. However, TCM acupuncture and moxibustion was deeply loved and still widely used by the general public because its low cost, convenient application and good efficacy. In the meantime, great number of far-sighted personages represented by Cheng Dan&#8217;an established acupuncture and moxibustion societies and schools to cultivate the talents, which made certain contributions to protect and promote acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Academic Boom Period</h2>



<p>After the founding of the People&#8217;s Republic of China, the cause of TCM as well as acupuncture and moxibustion appeared an unprecedented prosperity, for the party and the state formulated the policy to develop TCM. TCM universities, hospitals and research institutes have been set up all over the country. Acupuncture and moxibustion is a compulsory course for students in TCM universities, and acupuncture and moxibustion department is a must in TCM hospitals.</p>



<p>In the early 1980s,schools of acupuncture and moxibustion were established in TCM universities, with unified national textbooks. And the cultivation of master and doctoral students in acupuncture and moxibustion was carried out, thus formed a complete system of teaching, medical treatment and scientific research in acupuncture and moxibustion.</p>



<p>Since April 1945,when Yan‘an Bethune International Peace Hospital first established acupuncture and moxibustion department in China&#8217;s general hospitals, so did many western medicine hospitals. Likewise, some western medicine universities have also provided acupuncture and moxibustion courses, and some provinces and cities even have set up acupuncture and moxibustion hospitals or branch hospitals. With the vigorous development of acupuncture and moxibustion, its teaching, medical treatment and scientific research have achieved fruitful results. In the early 1950s,the academic focus was mainly on organizing the literature, observing the indications, and expounding the knowledge system with modern scientific methods.</p>



<p>In the late 1950s and 60s, the academic center of acupuncture and moxibustion was</p>



<p>shifted to the monographic research of ancient literature, the massive observation and summary of its curative effect for modern diseases, the comprehensive experimental research (to observe its effect to the organ functions of each system and to reveal its basic functions) and the theoretical research of acupuncture anesthesia and analgesia.</p>



<p>Since the 1970s,with the application of neurophysiology, anatomy, histochemistry. biochemistry, immunology, molecular biology and advanced modern scientific and technological means such as sound, light, electricity, magnetism and so on, the relevant issues of acupuncture and moxibustion have been researched in depth, specially the treatment mechanism and analgesia principle. The indications of acupuncture and moxibustion treatment were also expanded. Clinical practice shows that acupuncture and moxibustion has various degrees of therapeutic effect to more than 300 kinds of disease, covering internal, external, gynecological, pediatric, ophthalmological and otorhinolaryngological, orthopedic and traumatological disease, about 100 of which even with good or perfect curative effect. Many scholars have also made modern researches on acupuncture manipulations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
